All right.
The crack has returned.
The shakes will be over soon.
No more withdrawals.
This is my time.
What's going on?
From first we feast?
What's up?
Are you gonna win today, son?
I think so.
I feel good today.
Man, I've been feeling really good lately, actually.
I think I'm gonna get a lot of wins today.
I'm gonna dominate this game today.
I'm gonna make it my bitch.
Yeah, you heard that right.
I'm gonna pick Isaac and I'm gonna just keep winning.
Never losing.
Yes, and I'm gonna do greed.
I'm gonna try the next difficulty.
Maybe also some of those challenges or achievements or whatever they were called.
Just to see what's going on, you know, up there in Boston.
I've got green tea with a bit of honey today and water.
No coke.
Can't do it.
It's not that I'm a big fan of tea.
It's just that I heard it's good when you're being a healthy boy.
That's why I'm drinking it.
I tried to do it without anything.
Just the teabag, you know.
It do add a bit of sugar, but that kind of defeats the whole purpose of not eating sugar.
Alright, let's go with honey.
Closest thing to it, right?
You ready to gamble potatoes?
Oh, right.
You guys are gambling on these runs.
Maybe you should just throw them randomly just to fuck you guys up.
Nah, I would never do that.
Obviously, I'm always doing my best.
It's not like I'm out here standing in a in a Molotov on purpose, you know.
I don't do that stuff.
That's messed up.
No match fixing here.
Okay.
Oh, man.
Isaac, the binding of... I don't even know what binding means.
So hold on, the binding of Isaac.
Are we talking about like a bandage binding?
What does binding mean?
Do you guys know what binding means in this context?
Capturing?
You mean like a cowboy throwing his rope?
Binding him up?
Wrapping?
The wrapping of Isaac.
That sounds delicious.
With some beans, some chilies, some meat.
Oh wait, Isaac is the meat.
We got those beautiful butt cheeks.
You started playing Isaac because of me?
You're addicted?
Well, there we go.
I think it's kind of cool that I'm inspiring people to play the games I'm playing.
I mean, you inspired me to play this and I'm also inspiring you guys to play it.
Like, I'm having a blast with it.
I'm glad you guys are too.
I'm assuming most of you have played it though.
Remember, Isaac is a kid.
Stop talking about his ass.
Isaac is Isaac, okay?
He's a made-up character.
He has an ass.
Everyone has asses, okay?
Who cares?
Isaac?
What?
No, Isaac.
Oh wait, am I saying it wrong?
It's Isaac, right?
This game is like butts, poop, pee, and violence all in one.
There's so much poop in this game.
And guess what, guys?
You can't have poop without a butt.
Am I right?
That's so stupid.
Okay, let's get into it.
Let's see here.
Oh yeah.
Guys, this game is too easy for me.
It's too easy.
I'm going for greed.
We gotta make it harder.
It's too easy.
Who do I pick though?
We also have Magdalene, Yum Heart, Luckfoot.
That one was the one that gave luck.
But there was also something else.
Guys, we may just start with a... with an assasal.
Just one assasal.
Just to kick things off.
On greed.
And then we'll see.
Then we'll see.
Whoa!
Okay, wait, there's a timer.
Wait, what the...
Okay, we have a treasure room.
No keys.
We have an angel room and exit.
We got gems on the floor.
Wait, what?
Zero out of ten coins.
Special coins.
A wooden spoon.
I'm so confused right now.
What is the point of this?
I'm gonna click this.
Oh yeah, the gym!
The gym button is working!
Holy shit!
I was like, wait a minute, is that...
Is that gym?
Amazing.
Okay, so there's enemies in here now.
This is so weird.
I don't understand this.
We keep getting money?
Ow.
Oh wait, I clicked it again.
Okay, good.
I have no idea what's happening.
Oh, come on.
Okay, we got three out of ten coins.
And we have the fool right now.
That will return me to the start, right?
Yeah.
Why is it called the fool though?
Wait, I'm so confused right now.
Wait, do I just keep pressing this button?
It's like a wave-type deal?
Enemies spawn in waves?
Haven't found a key yet though.
What the?
There's no rooms?
Ha!
That killed him!
Maybe you have to kill them before time runs out or something.
Oh god.
Okay.
I gotta bait him.
There we go.
Got baited.
Oh god.
Oh yeah, there's a timer that's going down again, again, again.
Like it keeps resetting.
So we got a bunch of money now.
This feels more like a challenge mode and not like an actual difficulty.
Wait, is this new now?
No.
How do I get keys?
Oh, what the?
You!
It's boss time.
Let's keep dodging.
Whoa!
Careful of the bomb.
We got him.
Oh, we got the horseman guy.
He spawns little guys.
Okay, okay.
Greed mode because of the money.
We get lots of money.
Oh god.
No, I got hit.
That bastard.
Oh man.
Okay, do your thing.
Sweet.
Wait, what is exit?
Wait a minute.
We gotta go by.
Thanks.
What's this one?
Mom's coin purse?
Random pills?
Spawn some spiders?
I don't really like any of these items.
Am I crazy?
We're gonna re-roll.
Mr. Dolly, that seems good.
That's good.
This one is... I don't know what that is.
I'm definitely buying that.
Oh, nice.
That's huge.
Amazing.
Oh, we can buy a key as well.
I'm gonna do it.
Then I'm gonna go in here.
Whoa.
Kamikaze?
Become the bomb.
Oh, it's an active.
Explode.
Warning damages Isaac too!
Okay, so this item sucks pretty much unless you have that item that heals pyromaniac.
And I don't have that, so it sucks.
Pretty much that's all it is.
If I click this now, there's like a red pentagram on it.
I have a bad feeling.
Whoa.
Well, what the... what is that?
This is Gemini.
Look at me remembering the names.
Maybe it's like a practice mode for the real game, you know?
Because this is super easy, you know?
We got a plus hundred on Angel.
But we've already been in here.
Oh, this is open now.
Oh, it's the same room.
Okay, okay, I see.
Oh no, I missed this one then.
Shit.
Can I press the button again?
No money for me.
What's that?
A lump of coal?
Ah, not that good.
The boomerang.
There's a boomerang that hits for two times Isaac's damage.
Hetrify his enemies and can collect pickups.
That sounds really good, actually.
But how do I continue the game?
I'm confused.
Do I have to go in here?
Spawns two red hearts.
I don't really like that.
Also, I can just do this and get out of here.
I guess I'm gonna try and exit.
Okay.
Oh, shit.
Okay, okay, okay.
So we're moving on.
Okay, so it is actually... we're at... we are gaming.
Okay, okay.
Oh, man.
It's incredible what honey can do to a T, huh?
Oh, wait, I... oh, oh.
Oh, so we do another one of these.
Aha!
We get the money.
I don't know if I need to collect the money immediately or if I can just sort of leave it.
Now I'm gonna leave it, see what happens.
Oh, god.
Oh, they throw bones.
Okay, yeah, they keep spawning the money.
Good.
Man, Azazel is just fantastic.
Love Azazel.
We can totally nuke them as soon as they spawn.
Now we got a bunch of money.
So we go in here.
Yo, I wonder if all these things I'm finding here is gonna be saved for my actual runs.
You know, like, if I identify some of these.
This is only seven.
I don't know why it's red though.
Like, why is it called it red?
Also, we have eight out of ten coins.
Special coins.
Ah, I don't know what these are.
I think I'm gonna go for, um, I guess a key, right?
We needed a key?
Yeah, we need a key.
I'll take that.
Uh,
damage of tears.
Fire from Isaac's left eye.
Okay, that's fine.
Beautiful.
I'm gonna go buy more.
I think I'll take this one.
Spin to win.
Let it rip.
Okay.
While held, grants an orbiting top familiar that blocks enemy shots and deals contact damage.
Significantly increases speed at the top's spin speed and contact damage while the active item button is held.
No, I hate the held thingy.
This item charge depletes gradually.
Man, I'm having trouble reading this text because it's a little blurry.
Recharge is automatically while the active item button is not held.
Okay, interesting.
Okay, got it.
Ah, all right.
That's kind of interesting.
Oh, those are bombs.
Whoa, I'm super fast as well when I'm spinning.
There's more.
Wait, unless I didn't do it in time.
I'm a little confused.
I hate this guy when he whistles at me.
Okay.
Wait, wait, wait.
What's the difference?
We got a white treasure room and an angel room.
Whoa, hold on.
Seraphim.
That's a good one.
Okay, we also have this.
But I wonder how that works, I guess, when we go to the next floor.
The torn photo.
Tears and shots speed up.
I like it.
The spinning top sucks.
I hate it.
Oh, wait, there's more.
Bloodshot eye.
I want to see what this is, but I don't have enough money.
I need a little bit more.
It's got to be like a coin somewhere.
Maybe in this room.
I'm gonna take damage upon leaving though.
Hmm, maybe not worth it then.
Let's take a...
I don't know, man.
I guess we're moving on.
11 out of 10, by the way, on the coins.
Okay, we don't have a key.
We can go in here immediately.
The halo all stats up.
That sounds pretty good.
Pretty fitting with the angel that we have behind us.
Lucky toe, more luck.
Chance to add an additional pick up to chests, tinted rocks and destroyed machines.
Speaking of destroyed machines, I should destroy some machines.
I could also re-roll some stuff.
Wait, I have no bombs.
Okay, uh, right.
Let's just go.
That was so good.
Wow, that was close.
Wait, where are you?
Oh,
nice.
Ah, but the white ones can't... There we go, kill him.
Oh, we got more!
I'm kind of gaming right now.
Oh, hell yeah.
Give me that money.
32 monies.
Midnight snack, more health.
That seems really good.
We do like that.
Oh, that replaces the belt.
Wait, what?
Oh, wait, no, no, no.
It spawned a new one.
Oh, hmm.
Do we want luck, though?
Could be good.
Could be good to get some luck.
What is this one?
Dealing damage to enemies, gradually recharges active items.
At a rate of one charge, active items no longer gain charges from room clears.
I'm going to re-roll.
Jesus juice?
That's good.
We like Jesus juice.
Oh, we keep getting new ones.
That's so awesome.
Okay, well, we need more money.
And we need a key.
Uh, the next thing I buy is going to be the key.
What are you doing?
Okay.
Wait, you ain't doing nothing.
What is even that?
Oh, whoa, whoa.
I didn't even see that guy.
Okay, get this one.
What is this?
Uh, we don't know.
The scooper scoops out the eye, turning it into a peeper familiar.
The current room hears from the right eye socket deal 50% more damage.
I mean, I guess it's better than the stupid spinning top.
I'm not quite sure how exactly.
Oh, wait, I can't control it right.
Okay, fine.
Oh, there's two of them.
Wow.
Oh, I saw that coming actually.
We got him.
Okay, so this opened.
Do we take a deal with the devil?
I feel like we already get so many items.
It's not even worth it.
Or maybe it is.
Let's just have a look.
Pentagram.
More damage increases devil angel room chance.
That seems good.
Sister Maggie, familiar that fires tears for six damage.
I kind of want... Oh wait, I can just take this one too for free, right?
Nice.
Don't accidentally pick up the wrong thing.
The fool, nice.
And yeah, I'll take the pentagram.
We're doing it.
And then I'm gonna go in here, grab this, and we're gonna fool our way out of here.
Amazing.
We have eight coins left.
I think I'll buy another key.
Yeah, no, wait, wait, wait.
I'm gonna blow this up.
Whoa!
The panic button.
Just before taking damage of charge to automatically use Isaac's active item.
Okay.
Why not?
So we're done on this floor.
Right, there's nothing else to do.
Eight coins.
I could buy this.
Yeah, why not?
Member card has appeared.
So I wonder if some of these unlocks simply happen based on various thresholds, you know?
Like you have picked up X amount of items.
You've killed so many enemies.
You've won the game so and so many times, you know?
It's probably all very complicated.
Exactly how it works.
Damn it!
Oh wait, I can fly.
Hmm.
Was there a bomb in here?
There's no bomb.
Shit.
Ah man, I want these chests real bad.
I could run into it.
But that's gonna... nah.
Nope, we're going.
So apparently we're going to the universe now or whatever this is.
Maybe the womb.
Maybe the shin or the knee.
I don't know.
It's the womb.
Okay.
Interesting, let's see what they have here.
They got pills.
Carts.
And a button.
But I am flying, so we're totally chilling.
Jim.
Oh man, that's nice.
Look at this hood right here.
Eight ball.
Shot speed.
Chance of planetariums.
I don't even know what planetariums are.
Would love to see a planetarium.
Okay, let's just go I guess.
Oh no, in here first.
Bob's rotten head.
Let's Isaac throw a poison bomb.
I mean, if that destroys things, it's really good.
If it destroys rocks and stuff.
A booster pack.
What do we have?
Death?
Hierophant?
Oh, that's good.
Let's get those.
Two of hearts.
Double Isaac's red hearts.
We don't need that now.
Justice.
One heart.
Oh, that's nice as well.
Justice.
Uh oh.
Okay, fine.
The Empress for the current room gained damage.
So is that gonna work on the entire floor then, or what?
Now it says room, right?
Let me go in here and try it.
We put this on.
Now we go crazy.
No problem.
I hate these guys.
The fact that there's a timer for these makes me think that if you don't manage to kill them within the time, then something bad happens.
I don't know what yet though.
I think I've been winning pretty steadily.
There we go.
Tomatoes.
Kill them all.
Nice.
Oh yeah.
Look at me harvesting.
Okay, 22 coins.
This one was shot speed.
That's not bad.
Let's try this.
Item martyr.
Okay.
Recharges one bar of Isaac's active item each time he takes damage.
That's horrible.
I hate that item, but I like the way it looks.
Got it.
Uh what else can we buy?
Let's let's buy a pill.
I like it.
Pheromones.
Pheromones?
Not sure what that is.
It's probably not good.
Uh okay.
Now I think we had a couple more cards.
Yeah, give me that one.
We can use this in here.
Oh, we took damage?
I don't know how.
Everyone die.
Not bad.
Oh wait, so so hold on.
It stopped early.
I think we didn't manage to do it.
We messed it up.
So time is at zero now.
I'm not sure what that means.
Something's off here.
Oh, there's no time now.
Okay, this is no timer.
Oh, they have a lot of HP.
Oh man.
Oh man!
I'm in danger!
Ah!
Fuck me!
I'm gonna die in here.
Yeah, it's over.
Wow, that room was crazy.
What the hell?
Okay, I'm not a big fan of that mode.
I don't like it very much.
I'm gonna go play normal.
Actually, let's try the challenge thing.
Challenges.
Pitch black.
That doesn't sound good.
Highbrow.
Pet trauma.
The tank.
Solar system.
I want that.
Oh, I see.
We got planets orbiting.
I can't shoot.
What the fuck?
Distant orbital fly that deals damage.
Familiar.
Grant two pretty fly orbital familiars.
Grant's flight.
Well, at least we can fly.
Alright.
Wait, really?
Come on, guys.
Deal some damage.
The solar system.
Alright, the solar system is doing solid.
What's this door?
Look at that one.
I'm gonna blow it up.
We need one more.
I'll be back.
Man, it's so weird that I can't shoot.
But I can fly, baby, so I can sit in here.
I like the blue one the most.
What the fuck?
Okay, there we go.
Did we see anything suspicious in here?
Not really.
No, the flies cannot destroy poop.
This is a massive debuff.
Oh, wait.
We're friends with people.
Why is that?
Let's see here.
None of these.
I don't know why that is.
They're my friends.
I guess I'm just the master of flies.
All my flies are homies.
Nice.
So they just keep following me.
Yo, that's sick.
Two of these?
What the frick?
Okay, why not?
All right, stay in the center and just orbit.
Come on, planets.
Boss is here.
I have no money, so it's not gonna make any sense to go.
I do a bomb, though.
I'm gonna destroy this door in the beginning.
What is this game mode, man?
Yeah.
Oh, wait.
I've been here before.
There's a picture of poop on the wall and someone being hanged.
Hey, picture of a fly.
How's that, huh?
This must be my room, then.
I love flies.
I don't know what's the point of this place.
Okay.
Well, we're gonna experiment with that stuff later, because I don't really know what to do now.
Maybe we'll get a clue at some point.
Boss is gonna be interesting.
The haunt.
All right, flies.
Let's go for it.
This is the foreskin man.
Just gotta avoid and hope for the best.
Nice.
Ah, I'm an idiot.
That was bad.
Whoa, dude, the fly steals significant significant amounts of damage.
Not bad at all.
Um, I got no money somehow.
This is kind of cool.
I like this.
I like that we're blind as well.
Look at that.
Oh, man, they do a lot of damage.
What the hell?
The solar system is kind of nuts.
This is a little bit scary, though.
Damn.
Uh, I guess I'm gonna use the blue one.
Ah, you gotta be kidding me.
How did that happen?
Here, enjoy the blue.
I gotta find even more flies.
I didn't mean to enter here, but maybe it's okay.
What happened?
What just happened?
Okay.
This room is a mystery.
Like, it never seems worth it to do, you know?
The amount of pain you go through to get a shitty reward is insane.
How is this ever good?
Yeah, come on, guys.
Come to me.
Come on, then.
What are you afraid of?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Ahoy!
Sweet.
Ah, well, you can't hit me here.
Actually, we gotta tell something.
Can he hit me?
He can't!
I'm immune here!
Okay, it doesn't look like I'm immune, but I guess I am.
Uh, we do have a key, but we have no money, so...
Oh, shit!
Oh, god, no thanks.
Oh, nice.
The fact that we can fly, though.
Wait a minute.
Is that the pun here?
We can fly, because we have flies?
The moon, teleport to the secret room!
Yes, please.
Cool.
Uh, no bombs, though.
Oh, my god, really?
Oh, wait, am I gonna... Yeah, I do take damage!
Fuck!
Why do I take damage when I can fly?
That's bullshit, man.
I did not hit her.
Uh, okay, now we leave.
We'll leave.
Actually, wait.
No, we'll leave.
We'll leave.
Get out of here.
Okay.
Oh, the fly is my friend!
Yo, the Duke of Flies is my bitch!
That is insane!
Very nice.
Uh, the speedball is gonna be useless for me, because I can't shoot shit.
I wonder, though, what if I find, uh, the laser?
Can I suddenly shoot now, or what?
If that happens.
Three chests.
Empty.
Cursed eye!
Chart shot that fires up to five tiers in a burst.
Taking damage mid-charge teleports Isaac to a random room.
And a pill.
Oh, I want... Oh, we can't destroy the fire, though!
Okay, we're fine.
Speed... Nah, that sucks.
What's this?
Hey, nice!
I'm actually gonna take this.
But it seems like we're not losing HP.
We're taking it.
So what's the deal?
Wait, can I shoot?
No, okay.
All right, moving on, I guess.
Okay, I... I'm trying to see the perspective you guys are talking about there.
With them not having tits or whatever it is.
It's very hard.
I almost can't see it.
We stay in the water.
That's right.
Come on, flies.
Dude, I had no idea the flies were this good.
I'm gonna start to appreciate the flies I find way more.
Oh, wait, that's a friend.
Wait, is it a friend?
It's a friend.
Okay.
Oh, wait, we have a guide down here.
But I can't destroy this poop!
What do I do?
I guess I could blow it up.
I'm not gonna do that, though.
It's gonna be a tough one.
That's a tinted rock!
We need the blue one for this guy.
Ah, fuck you, fuck you, fuck you.
It's okay.
Come to me.
Beautiful.
I'm using the blue.
I'm too scared.
Wonderful.
Speed down, no thanks.
I'm not gonna eat that.
Come on.
This one's gonna be tough, maybe.
No, it's not.
Just about being paid.
Why did that hit me?
I'm gonna wait for the blue to be in configuration.
There we go.
Okay, we got one.
Fuck me, dude.
This is so difficult!
Kill him!
Okay, there we go.
Nice.
Tough one.
Going down here.
Not doing boss yet.
Wow, look at all these extra rooms.
Easy.
Gym.
I gotta make bombs!
Oh, thank you for that!
Thank you!
Uh-oh.
Oh, I got hit twice in a row.
That's kind of bad.
Kill him.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
You want coins?
Uh, why not?
But I need something good in return.
Hey!
Not too shabby.
Gamble, gamble, gamble.
Okay, I'll take that.
Oh no, I spent all my money.
Oh, look at that one.
That is a sexy bomb.
Hmm, I don't want anything in here.
And what I mean is, I can't afford it.
Uh-oh.
That's fine.
Held up!
Yeah!
Huge.
Okay, the blue one's gonna be MVP now.
Nice.
Come on, blue one.
I need more neptunes and urinuses.
I don't want these venuses and mercuries.
Yeah, leave that pill behind.
We don't like that.
Oh, oh, but you can't hit me here!
That's too bad, son.
Wonderful.
This one should be hella easy.
Whoa, okay, okay.
All right, all right, all right, it's fine.
Wow!
I can't believe they hit me.
It is so weird playing like this.
But I kind of like it.
And now we go here.
Kill them fast, nice.
So the flies also absorb damage, it seems.
Is it all the flies or just some of them?
Feels contact damage.
I'm not sure, actually.
Okay, time to leave.
Uh, boss time.
This is either a massive success or a massive failure now.
Depending on the boss.
Give me Duke of Flies again.
Can it even happen twice in the same run?
I wonder.
The husk.
I forgot what he does.
But he has flies!
That's good for me!
Heck yeah, heck yeah.
Come on, guys.
Get in there, get in there.
Oh god.
Let's not die here, huh?
Not bad.
And we got soap.
That is actually soap!
Fantastic!
Very nice.
Tears and... oh, well that's useless for me.
Unless it also affects my familiars that shoot projectiles.
This is one of my favorite dreams.
I like that one.
That's funny.
Why are their hearts on that door- oh, okay.
It was just a frozen fly.
Everything's cool.
Oh my god.
Okay, then.
Thank you.
Yeoyoyoyoyoyoyyyyyy buddy.
Come on now.
Kill that guy, killed him.
Man, tiny targets are a problem for me.
I'm good with some healing, though.
I need more flies.
Wait, they're friends?
What if they blow up, though?
Oh, I guess they are technically bombs.
Fly bombs.
Huh.
Cool.
I'm gonna try and stay away from them in case they blow up on me.
I'm scared.
I'm very scared.
Come on, bombs!
Blow some shit up!
Useless!
What are they doing?
Okay.
That was an interesting room.
Strength!
Get more health, speed, damage,
and oh, they deal contact damage!
I see what it is.
Cool.
TNT.
I'm gonna use a key here.
We gotta go for the pill.
Always get the pill.
Very nice.
More familiars.
The solo system is gonna be so populated when we're done.
Did I just get hit?
Oh, I need that one, too.
Yeah!
We're kind of killing it!
Money!
A lot of it, too.
Dude, I feel so good.
We're just gonna go in here now.
Bring it on, the Fallen!
I'm gonna fuck you up, brother.
Oh, god.
Wow, okay, you do that.
Got it.
Wow!
Holy shit, brother!
This is impossible!
Deal some contact damage!
Come on!
Get that damage in there!
We're gonna die.
How does anyone win this?
This is insanity!
This boss is so difficult!
I can't with bullet hole games, man!
Or bullet hell.
Like, bullet hell games?
Fucking ruin my brain.
Like, when there's more than four bullets on the screen, it's over.
Like, I can't win.
It's horrible.
Um, I don't know what to pick.
I'm just gonna go with normal gameplay now.
I think I'll go with Magdalene again.
That's the one with, uh, what is it?
Oh, yeah, with the heal on demand.
Not bad.
Fucking hate bosses that have, like, a million projectiles.
And look at that, we get rich immediately.
Oh, oh, oh, already nine?
Uh, what do you do again?
Also, are you wearing a straight jacket?
Uh-oh.
Oh, this is gonna be...
Don't want to destroy too many of them at the same time.
Beautiful.
This is a tedious boss, or enemy.
Especially if you just have slow shots, like I just did.
What the?
Why are they moving like that?
What the fuck is this?
Huh?
That is way... They've never done that before.
Wait, I have another item.
What is this XL on the right?
Purple XL?
Huh.
More Golden Poop?
Damn.
We're gonna be able to buy everything.
Uh, should I blow... Yeah, obviously.
I thought it said something else.
Uh, okay.
Pause!
That sounds useful against a lot of bullets.
It freezes all enemies in the current room for up to 30 seconds!
The freeze effect ends early if Isaac fires a tear.
Oh.
Oh, wait, I don't know.
I kind of like my current setup there, but what I could do is use this comeback when I need healing and use that instead.
I think I like that more.
Uh, is it worth it to spend a bomb here?
I don't think so.
Come on.
Nice.
Flies used to be my friends, now they're my enemies.
D10.
Devolves all enemies in the room into other enemies of lower difficulty.
Oh, that's also a good one.
I like this one more, I think.
Yeah.
Oh, god.
Don't step in the green shit.
Ah.
Mistakes were made.
That was clean?
Oh, wait, if I destroy this with a bomb, I actually think I can access both.
Yep.
Incredible.
Isaac's bombs detonate faster.
Oh, I didn't actually want to pick it up.
That's an expensive placebo.
No, these are shit items, man.
When I finally have money, that's what I get.
No extra money for me.
Um, I guess I will donate.
Gotta start donating, right?
And now it broke.
Let's earn some more money.
Let's just go for it.
Headless Horseman.
Oh, I accidentally used my active.
I didn't realize in time that I was dealing with a boss, I guess.
I regretted it last minute.
What is happening?
I'm dying!
What am I taking damage from?
I was nowhere near them.
I don't understand what is happening, dude.
What the fuck?
Fuck.
Let's go with Isaac.
No, let's go random.
What are we getting?
Kain!
Nice.
Now, Kain is... I'm actually not sure what his deal is.
Do you have any items?
No items.
One key, two hearts.
Doesn't seem that good.
Oh, this again?
Aren't there like a million items in this game?
What is happening?
Come here.
Jumping jacks.
Look like little starfish.
I can get in there.
OK, we're doing good on money already.
And we get an item, too.
There's two items?
Like this item again?
Mom's razor.
OK, it's familiar.
Blocks enemy shots, deals contact damage, applies a bleed effect.
They take damage over time, basing their movement speeds, and leave trails of damaging red creep.
Damaging red creep for the enemies, I imagine.
And not for me.
Good.
Beautiful, I needed bombs.
Yep, I can get in here.
Yeah, that was a fast bomb explosion.
Nearly didn't have time to get out of the way.
I think we're going for it.
Dingle.
Because the guy's gonna whisper at me.
Or not whisper, whistle.
I always get those two words mixed up.
Yeah, you're exhausted now.
Just keep doing that, I like that.
Beautiful.
Here comes again.
Ah, motherfucker, I thought I could do you cleanly.
Then you had to change it up at the last minute, huh?
Oh well.
Still good.
Some cards.
Please let it be a secret room card for one of these.
Doubles, isics, red hearts, blood donation.
I mean...
More red hearts?
I mean, OK, in that case.
Maybe we can try it.
Spawn that.
Boink.
Nice.
Then we're gonna take this one.
Take that.
Look at me go!
And then we're gonna take...
Yeah, that one I guess.
And now we're gonna take this one.
Beautiful.
Must do damage.
Homing shots.
Probably better.
There's a shot.
OK, what do we got?
This one, what is that even?
Unknown card.
Compost, gain more friends.
It's an active.
Duplicates each blue spider and fly Isaac currently has.
That would be crazy on...
The solar system.
Destroys all pickups in the ground in the current room and picked up.
Grants one blue spider or fly for each one destroyed.
OK.
Weird.
Are these not considered pickups or what?
They were not destroyed.
Donating the money.
It's for a good cause.
And then I'm gonna blow this thing up.
Ooh!
Beautiful.
The devil, do I want that instead?
Plus two damage is significant.
It's like...
What is that?
50% extra damage or so?
I'm gonna...
Magician.
More range.
No, let's go for the damage.
More damage!
Can't go wrong with that.
I can't believe I got hit.
What did this one do again?
Oh, right.
I feel like it's horrible.
Like, how often do I have so many spiders?
Or flies or whatever it's at?
Oh, no!
Oh, how did I not get hit there?
Ayy!
Huge.
I feel like the Razor is too close to actually do anything significant.
Playing it safe here.
Nice.
Run!
These guys are just vibrating, huh?
Niiight!
Insane.
Master key!
But the fact that we hear a door open in the distance makes me think there's more to this key other than just conserving keys when you go through doors.
Like, there's some kind of big door somewhere.
And I want to find it.
Get out of that!
Wow, wow.
Okay.
Not going in there.
Of course I'm not doing that.
I need some help.
Man, these guys are hard to hit.
Jump out of there.
Oh, what is that even?
Why is he totally blue?
Whoa!
Fucking holy shit.
The range on that jump.
I might just die right now.
Fuck!
Wow!
Okay, so we...
Duplicate!
We have been duplicating flies.
What's that?
Blood bombs.
More health?
That's good.
So needed right now.
And then it did something else.
What was that?
Bomb explosion spawn a puddle of damaging red creep, allows blazing bombs when bomb counts at zero.
At the cost of health.
Okay.
You got it.
Uh, yep.
I lost all of my flies just now.
Man.
They go fast, huh?
A compass.
Ooh, I think that would be really good.
I wonder what that does.
Oh my god.
Yes, sir.
Worth it to... Ooh, dude, we can get to 15!
Worth.
We're gonna see what that item does.
The end is near.
Reveal special rooms on the map, no way.
Ho!
Okay.
But... not secret rooms?
If no secret rooms, then... useless?
Wait, what is happening?
Oh, they're taking damage.
More money.
Uh-oh.
A button.
Oh, how am I gonna...
Ah, I got hit.
Unbelievable.
I'm picking this up.
Bring it on, Gemini.
Oish.
He's taking damage from standing in the creep.
Like, I can barely tell what's creeping, what is not.
Like, look at the fucking floor, dude.
Looks like everything is creeping here.
Why did we just lose minus 35 on demon?
What do we do?
Are we not supposed to kill this guy?
The spoon, that's good.
Some speed up.
So the next one has a timer on it.
Man, I really do wonder...
Maybe, okay, new theory.
What if... those rooms that have a timer on them means that you need to get to that room within a certain time limit, and if you do, then something happens.
It's not about, you know, doing that floor super fast.
It's about doing everything else before that super fast.
Yeah, keep pooping, that's fine.
Good.
I shouldn't have picked up that heart.
I wasted half a heart there.
Flying tomatoes?
Whoa!
Bro, I can't hit anything.
Got a long range this...
Oh my goodness.
Come here.
Oh, man.
Whoo!
It's difficult.
These guys only shoot horizontal and down, okay.
Come on now, you bastard.
There we go.
Oh, we can actually beeline towards the item room.
The compass is actually not that bad.
The bad thing is we can't see the secrets.
That was so good.
Nice aiming.
We got a bomb.
Twelve gold as well.
Oh, this is... no, I don't know what that is.
Botfly, defense drone.
How come I didn't have that in my planets orbiting last time?
Orbital familiar that deals contact damage and fire shielded tears at incoming enemy projectiles.
Shielded tears?
Meaning that those tears cannot be destroyed, I guess.
So they will always win if it comes down to it.
Oh my god.
Fuck me, the fly just fucked me.
We also have the devil still.
I keep forgetting about that one.
Oh yeah, it's totally working.
Beautiful.
The backpack?
That's a different kind.
What's that gonna do?
Oh, I'm gonna blow this guy up and maybe get some money.
Yeah, it's not enough.
I'm gonna blow this up.
No!
I donated.
Yeah!
But I guess it's take... Okay, so we had 169, I believe.
Let's remember that.
169.
And I was holding two active items at once.
When holding two active items, press the swap button to switch.
Okay.
I don't like that.
I don't want to have... No, that was a waste, man.
I hate active items.
I clicked the wrong button.
No, it didn't.
It was okay.
I clicked the right button.
Now I'm gonna take this one.
Look at that!
Oh, all just to get a key.
Well, not quite worth it.
I need to find some better active items, dude.
Because the one I have right now is really bad.
Unless...
Why is it not duplicating my fly?
Freaking liar!
That's a lie right there.
Bro, will you die?
There you go.
Oh, wait a second now.
How are we... Oh, I know how.
Holy shit!
That is so cool.
We got a challenge room.
I like that.
That destroyed an enemy.
I'm gonna save that heart until I lost a bit more HP.
That was nice.
These are the hottest enemies in the game.
Man, that fly is really helping here.
It's doing good.
Fantastic.
We're taking this.
And we save the other heart.
Uh-oh.
Oh, this one is tough.
Or is it when we have this fly?
Motherfucker!
Fly, come on!
Oh, that was a bit risky what I did there.
That's okay though.
This room...
Should I?
I can get it back.
Okay, a pill.
Nice!
I'm drowsy?
Oh, I don't like that.
Oh, crap!
This guy, we can move.
Nice.
I'm gonna go like this.
More speed up.
Something's wrong.
Is that good though?
So it spawns black creep.
I do wonder if that is damaging to enemies.
Okay, now we go pick up the other heart.
There we go.
Man, I'm so fast, look at this!
Whoa!
Now I just need more shot speed as well, so I can actually hit things.
I feel like I'm too fast for my own good right now.
Uh, not here.
Oh, I could buy this!
Thanks.
Time for the boss.
Yeah, it didn't work.
Kane versus Chub.
We gotta kill the small guys first.
Good.
Engage the boss.
In fact, I'm gonna do this.
Oh my god, it didn't even hit him!
But he takes damage when he walks in it.
Come to me.
Yeah, fighting this stuff.
You like that?
Oh, the creep disappears.
He just burst a couple new ones.
This speed is really helping.
Uh, screw.
Tears and shot speed up.
Just like that?
Okay.
That's what I needed.
Fantastic.
Let's see if we can't find some active items that don't suck.
Oh, a chest room.
Uh-oh, we're definitely gonna do this here.
Okay.
Oh!
Oh man, I hate this.
Too much shit on my screen.
Can I walk in this?
It's mine, right?
Okay.
I'm getting in here.
Please be healing.
No.
Perhaps we get some healing here.
Nope.
But a lot of stuff.
Could come in handy.
I'm so scared of those guys.
Come on.
I'm a little out of range.
There we go.
I'm grateful that these guys don't have infinite range.
Yeah!
Oh wait, they're not gonna take damage from that, because they're flying.
Man, I feel no damage at all!
I'm tickling them.
I gotta find something.
Bob splatter!
Placing a bomb also creates a small pool of high damaging...
I mean, it already happens.
Yeah, I don't like the fast detonation.
I feel like I'm almost getting hit by it every time.
I'll keep this.
Beautiful.
Where's the HP, though?
Thanks!
The game hurt me.
Kill this guy.
Whoosh!
Man, I'm glad they didn't have lasers.
I think I would have been dead if that was the case.
Uh,
this guy's gonna explode.
Yep.
He's taking damage, right?
Okay.
Uh, what?!
God fucking dammit.
Ugh.
Go with Isaac.
So anti-climactic, man.
There's some bullshit on the floor.
Isaac time.
Isaac will hurt you.
He is super sad right now.
He's especially sad, so he has many tears.
Oh, these spiderwebs are actually kind of dangerous.
The world?
Reveal it all!
The mulligan.
They grow inside.
Chance to spawn a bluefly each time a shot damages an enemy.
Now, that sounds pretty good.
Depending on how high that percentage is.
Would be nice to have that item that duplicates.
The flies.
Uh, secret room.
Right here!
Wow!
Come here, guys.
Okay.
I'm gonna save these hearts.
Both of them.
Playing it super safe.
Ooh, that's a lot of money.
Is it worth it?
Hmm.
Uh, maybe not.
We're gonna wait.
Maybe we'll find something else that's even better.
Let's see if we can get something here.
What was that?
Oh, a Game Boy or something?
Oh, wait, we also have a room here.
Huh!
Weird empty rooms we got.
Get those out of here.
Yeah.
Half the rooms are just empty.
Uh, I guess we're gonna heal up.
Actually, get this to get two bombs.
Oh, yeah.
Smart.
Uh, now I can get this.
And we can also get a key if we wanted, but I don't want to.
Instead, I may just... nah, it's okay.
Oh, we could go in there.
That's worth...
Hey!
Very cool.
Now we can heal up with this one.
Uh, where is it?
Up here.
And now it's time for boss!
Solid first floor.
Can't be mad about that.
Blighted oven?
What?
Don't cook me, mister!
Oh, we got a little guy that shoots lasers.
I don't like that.
Laser dudes are my nemesis.
Oh my god, he's fast!
Whoa!
Not too bad, though.
Mr. Doll, I feel like I see this every single run.
Sweet.
Okay, so what am I looking at?
Okay, I can maybe see the arms.
Now that I look at it...
in more detail, I can see...
a potential where there's no tits.
Nice.
I'm gonna blow that up.
Totally worth.
Wait, am I shooting more stuff sometimes?
Wait, what is happening?
Oh, it's the mulligan!
Okay, okay.
It's not actually tears, it's flies that I'm shooting.
In a way.
The hourglass.
Yes.
I think I like pills more.
You're explosive!
Fuck me!
Alright!
Well, goodbye to that heart.
That's very unpleasant.
I think the mulligan is pretty good.
It feels good.
I'm getting lots of bombs.
That's a special rock!
Nice.
Bro, how are you supposed to do this?
Very nice.
Boss time?
Why not?
I kinda wanna just try and go as fast as I can.
So try out my theory of the timers on the levels.
This guy is no big deal.
No big deal.
A spoon is good.
Even more speed.
Ooh, we got a thingy.
Ooh, moon and stars?
Shovel?
Or a little...
I don't even know what that is, some kind of brush.
Oh, wait.
I don't trust like that.
I'm gonna take this.
Curse up.
Uh...
It doesn't sound good.
Activates a demon form that grants damage and speed up when at half red heart remaining or less.
Oh, Whore of Babylon!
Whoa!
Effect is permanently active if Isaac has no red hearts.
So that's what's happening!
I'm a whore now!
Time to sell my body!
To get those gold coins.
I'm actually... Dude, I'm actually gonna take more items here.
Just to synergize with that.
Is that crazy?
Am I crazy?
Am I insane?
Headless baby.
Following familiar that generates a trail of damage and creep.
I like it.
Death List has appeared.
Uh-oh.
Creates a trap door to the next floor or to a crawl space.
Is it just random?
I'm confused.
Give me.
Well, uh, we have now become the whore.
And we have no more red hearts, so you know.
It's gonna be interesting.
Wait, we have not found a treasure room here.
We gotta go find that.
It is a must.
This is not gonna go well, by the way.
Or maybe it is.
Money.
Requires a key.
I don't...
Ah, should I?
Okay.
Why not?
You want coins, huh?
But they also want coins.
I kinda wanna blow some stuff up, but I'm gonna give you coins.
Oh god.
Oh, nice.
Thanks!
That was my last coin.
Hey!
Money.
We can keep gambling.
Wait,
what is that poster in the bottom?
Cults.
Cool?
Something coil.
Ah, okay, fine.
I'm gonna blow you up.
Oh, that's sick.
Actually worth.
Wow!
This arcade was amazing!
Rarely do I get to see an arcade as good as this.
And we found the treasure room as well.
What is that?
I've seen that before.
Tammy's head.
Fires a ring of ten tears.
That's an active, isn't it?
Yeah.
What else does it do?
It's just that.
Okay.
Let me actually try it real quick.
Got it.
Ah, it doesn't seem terribly good though, does it?
Like, it's just one shot, and it's not that much damage, I guess.
It creates a trapdoor to the next floor, or to a cr...
I mean, I'm interested about the crawlspace.
That is what I'm really interested about.
And you know what?
If I'm in a bad spot, I'm gonna use it and just leave.
Right?
I just say, fuck it.
I'm out.
Come here.
Nice.
Okay.
Dude, we have so many bombs.
Fuck!
Look at the light coming from above.
Here.
We can't trust the light.
Don't trust the light.
I'm gonna try this now.
Wait, we killed the balls already, right?
So...
Oh, I don't immediately go.
I see.
So if I get more mana, I can technically do it again on this floor.
We're gonna experiment with that.
I'm actually really curious about the shovel here.
Okay, we gained more damage.
I think it's because we are the whore.
Whores deal a lot of damage.
Okay.
Ooh, this is a tough one.
We gotta snipe them.
No reason to be risky here, just chillax.
Let them run into my shots.
Yeah, seven is fine.
Now, look, I could buy this battery.
Little baggy.
Isaac can hold two pills.
All future card drops are replaced with pills.
Oh!
I like that a lot, actually.
Maybe we have to save up for that.
We're gonna be pilling it up this time.
Yep.
That's the plan.
Let's go this way.
Oh, we got the weird jiggity jiggity jiggity juice!
Jiggity-doo!
Oh, man.
Oh, this is gonna be hard.
Killed them all.
Dude, are you gonna come over here?
Stop spawning those things.
Man, that guy was tangy.
What?
Holy.
Gluttony.
Aw, shit.
Nice, that went pretty well.
He dropped the poop.
I can't get in there.
What a tragedy!
No!
Unbelievable.
Nice.
So, wait, hold on.
There's something about those bombs.
They can be sort of moved around with my own bombs.
Or maybe even my body.
I gotta start thinking about that.
That's a bra?
Mom's bra?
Mass?
What is that?
Paralysis?
Temporarily petrifies all enemies.
Why is that?
I'd rather have this, honestly.
We're gonna go dig for treasure.
Let's try it here.
Okay, so that is next level.
Yeah.
Wow.
Did he just kill his friend?
That's amazing.
Hey, there you go.
Boss time?
Not yet.
Or then again, hold on.
Maybe I need to start thinking strategically about this.
So, for instance, right now, I have already found the treasure room.
I have not found the secret room.
But do we even... you know what?
Let's just continue.
I'm trying something new today.
We are experimenting a little bit here.
Pestilence.
Are you gonna start flying across the map?
Oh, wow.
So, I cannot hit the green shit.
Is he gonna start flying?
When do you fly?
When will you fly?
Maybe he's not that guy.
A cube of meat.
I feel like that is so underwhelming.
I also don't understand it quite.
Block shots.
And fire shots.
How am I ever gonna find four of these in a row?
Like, that is... impossible.
In a game with this many items?
How is anyone ever gonna find four of those?
Okay.
Ooh, should I save my money?
Or should I go for it?
Destroy it.
I think it's worth it to destroy this.
Oh, yeah!
Look at all that money, man!
Whoo!
Hell, yeah, uh-oh.
Man, these guys are tough as hell.
Got him.
Oh, jumping jacks!
Okay, it's not scary anymore.
AAA battery automatically restores the final charge of an active item.
Eh.
Okay, it's a trinket.
In fact, let's do that.
Okay, so that is...
the next level, right?
Yeah.
I wonder if, like...
Maybe there's indicate...
Oh, wait a minute!
There's sometimes X's on the floor.
X marks the spot.
Remember, I tried bombing it.
We're gonna try digging for that.
Oh, my God, I may be onto something here.
We've seen that multiple times.
I think I get it.
Eh-heh-heh.
Stop crying.
How rude.
What the hell is this room?
I'm drowsy, I don't like that.
Maybe I should wait out the effect.
Uh, I think it reduced my speed a little bit.
Bro, I hate this guy so much!
I may actually die in this room.
There's two of these guys now.
Okay, I got the spiders!
We're safe.
Oh, I'm so deathly afraid.
Beautiful.
No, not that one.
Don't like short fuse.
So, check it out.
We haven't found treasure room yet, so we're not gonna continue.
I want the treasure, baby.
Uh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Let me look around here.
None of these look like clear X's to me.
I'm gonna keep looking.
Maybe up here.
I feel like whenever I saw them before, they were quite obvious.
Like, some of these look like X's, but not really enough to convince me.
Oh, this is... yeah, I'm not getting that.
Ah!
Jiggly!
How the fuck did you dodge that crap?
Wow.
What do we have here?
Punching bag?
Scapegoat?
Wandering familiar that blocks enemy shots.
Enemies will sometimes focus their attacks on it instead of Isaac.
Whee!
That was a bit risky.
Bomb for me?
I'm gonna go in here because I'm rich as hell.
That's the steam sail.
Reduced price.
Oh, is that what ret means then?
When the items have a ret font, it means they have been reduced in price.
Aha!
I'll take this.
The sun!
This one is insane.
So when it says fully heals Isaac, I wonder if that counts with the blue hearts and black hearts.
I doubt it.
Man, the sun is insane.
It has all kinds of features built in.
I could also reveal this map now if I wanted, but no.
We're gonna wait.
Fuck me!
How?
Okay, he's dead.
Wow, I nailed it!
Nice!
Wait, hold on.
Oh, I can't go back.
I can't go back.
I'm in a corner.
The scapegoat is working!
Oh, thanks.
Can't use that for anything.
Let's look for an axe.
Like, this looked like an axe here, you know, but it's not like fully convincingly an axe.
So it's not like striking, you know?
This door is closed.
Man, what determines that?
I wonder.
What if it's related to the room over here with the spikes?
Like, if I step on the spike...
Maybe, no, I don't want to risk it, actually.
I have too much to lose.
Let's go for the boss.
Yeah, nothing looks suspicious here.
Let's go for it.
It's fistula.
I do not remember what you do.
All right.
This is actually kind of a difficult boss.
Oh my goodness.
Push.
Very good.
Smooth.
More range.
Spawns a red hard, that's not too good.
Oh, we could go in here.
Should we do it?
Oh, ocular.
Three!
We can't take any of this.
We're going to die if we do it.
Rip.
Ripperino.
Can I blow this guy up?
Why can't I blow him up?
Maybe he needs more bombs.
All right, I guess we move on.
I think next floor is mom.
We're not there.
Curse of the law.
Oh, no.
Not that.
Oh, this is tough.
Man, the scapegoat is working wonders here.
That is massive.
And this extra range helps so much, too.
Beautiful, beautiful.
I'm going to get so lost, by the way, on this floor.
Funnel them in.
What is the scapegoat doing?
Oh my God.
This room is crazy.
This guy looks like a pastry.
Of some sort, doesn't he?
With cream on top.
Let's just... Okay, wait a minute.
So, door here, door here.
Let's go north first.
Also, let's look for access.
I think I'm onto something with that.
Triple X, baby!
Duplicate X.
Look at that.
Yeah, it is super obvious.
Come on, kill them all.
How come the floor is still going?
Oh, I thought these couldn't die.
I thought they would break apart.
You see that?
You saw I pushed it?
That's the trick here.
Wait, that looks like just to the next stage.
I'm not entirely sure.
I'm going to wait...
until I'm done with this.
I'm honestly not entirely sure there.
I don't want to leave yet.
That's it.
I don't have a map.
Okay, so we haven't gone south yet.
Oh god.
Nice dodge.
Where did you come from?
What the heck?
I feel like these guys should be my friends because of my familiar.
How come I'm not befriending them?
The little jumping jacks, I mean.
Okay, got a key and a way to the right.
Whoa, what's happening?
Was I standing in something?
How the fuck am I supposed to tell the difference between mine and theirs?
Ah, look at this!
Oh, shit.
Ah, nevermind.
I don't like that.
Oh, the scapegoat is totally working!
Someone behind me?
No, okay.
The scapegoat is just hanging out over there.
That was actually so well done.
Just now, I'm proud of myself.
Matchbook!
Whoa, they shot both directions!
That's cool.
Evil up!
Oh, oh!
Bullet hell.
It's manageable.
Oh, nice.
Yeah, we did it.
Okay, so wait a minute.
What is the one I had right now?
AAA battery.
I guess it's fine.
Oh, man, did we go to a treasure room?
I don't think we did yet.
Wow!
Fuck!
Dude.
Okay.
Now we're back at the beginning, I think.
Ah!
All right.
We lost some HP there.
Mom!
This is a bad thing.
Where's Mom?
Mom?
How is anyone going to dodge that?
My goodness.
It is not looking good.
I think I'm going to move on to the next level, dude.
I can't even heal.
Oh, I'm in deep shit.
Oh, yeah, right.
We also had...
Oh, let me try this then.
There's a difference.
This one?
Hey, okay, okay.
Ladder...
Oh, wait.
We have a...
There's a guy here.
Oh, my God.
What is this?
Speed and range up.
I mean, that's cool.
But I would love to get some HP of some sort.
That would be ideal.
Guess I just jump down?
Wait, did I even defeat a boss here?
Can you actually just skip the boss like that?
Necropolis.
I'm having trouble seeing which one is my character.
Like, there's too much shit on my screen.
Oh, my God.
My focus is peaking right now.
Give me some HP, man.
Not that kind.
I am in such deep trouble.
I'm looking for suspicious rocks right now.
And other thing...
Oh, look at this!
I don't have enough mana.
I'll come back.
Oh, my God.
I need to go for it.
Okay, so wait, wait, wait.
Save spots.
I can't see what they're shooting because of my familiar.
Wait.
Wow!
Mom, mom, mom, mom, mom!
Any more moms?
Wow.
Evil flame, get it out of here.
Oh, I got plenty keys.
Let me in.
Child leash?
Familiars follow more closely behind Isaac.
Familiars gain a damage multiplier.
Cool, I guess.
Disturbing.
Oh, shit, that room is...
Go down here.
Wow!
Thank God I had the damage for that one.
Holy crap, I'm gonna blow everything up.
What's up, little fly?
Wow.
We can try this now.
Ladder?
That means we can go down.
Yeah.
Oh, wait, this is...
Okay, there we go.
Libra.
Minus speed, tears.
Ooh, that's a lot of damage.
Less range, though, but I have a lot of range.
Ooh, that's good.
Stat upgrades are balanced among all stats.
I think this may have been a net positive.
I'm unsure.
Oh, the attack speed!
Oh, yeah, it feels way better.
Okay, this way.
Yeah, the range is still very good.
Look at my range.
Somehow it took damage.
I don't know why or how.
What had happened?
I feel like I've had this room before.
I'm getting Major Deja Vu right now.
I'm playing this so incredibly safe.
Come on, little guy.
Oh, fuck this.
No!
Die, hell!
Yeah, bitch!
We got Play-Doh.
Why not?
Uh-oh.
Okay, that's fine.
Gym.
Oh, my gosh.
Got Evil Fire as well.
I can't get it.
Yes, I can get in there.
We're gonna gamble our hearts out now.
I can't get in there?
Why not?
Why can't I get in?
Huh?
Wait a minute.
Gotta be some way in here.
Fuck me.
We're going for it.
We're dead, though.
Half a heart is not good here.
Like, it is... yeah, it's over.
Oh, that's rough, man.
That was a crazy run.
Like, I was on the verge of just dying.
Constantly.
Eulith.
Why is it a box?
Why is it in a box?
I don't understand that.
Lazarus.
Samson.
Is there a character I haven't tried yet?
Magdalene.
No, I think we... how do I even...
Unlock by beating question mark.
Okay, that tells me a lot, thank you.
Now I know what to do.
Unlock by beating heart mode with Lazarus without losing a life.
Okay.
Unlock by beating two levels without taking damage.
Okay, that one should be...
You know what, we're gonna try and unlock Samson here.
Wait, can I put it on normal and actually unlock this?
Why wouldn't I do that?
I just... I just go asasal and normal.
Hello?
I'm confused.
Two levels... wait, two levels?
You mean two floors?
I'm actually confused.
What exactly is meant by two levels?
I'm not sure what that means.
Came...
Unlock by beating question mark.
Heart mode with a Lazarus without losing a life.
That is maybe possible, but also very impossible.
Lazarus, where are you?
Let's try it.
We can't lose a life.
This is the main objective.
We can't lose a life, and if we do take damage, the second objective is to win, right?
There's a lot of goodies in there.
Man, oh man, I have no bombs.
Kill those little guys.
I think there's a random chance for it to spawn some of these small ones when you kill them.
It's not always.
So not losing a life.
I wonder if it means, like, dying, because right now I'm playing Lazarus, which means I will resurrect.
Is that what's considered a life?
It must be, right?
Since Lazarus is the character in question that we have to play with.
So it's not like taking any damage.
It's not dying once.
That seems pretty doable, honestly.
Leo, Isaac can break most obstacles by walking over them!
Oh yeah!
I like that.
That's nice.
No items, though.
Too bad.
Oh my god.
So they only spawn flies when they're scared.
I think.
Oh, I can just eat everything.
Haha!
Now I can really check whether or not there's items in these pots or not.
How am I dodging?
That was insane!
Like, hello?
I'm kind of owning right now.
Where's this one?
Poke go.
Oh, right.
That one.
Oh yeah, destroy the rocks.
Eat all the rocks.
Amazing!
He met Timis's.
That didn't do anything, I guess.
I actually forgot what that did.
Oh, I can't break these ones, though!
Aha!
So not everything is breakable, huh?
Once again, I was lied to.
So many lies.
Yeah, that was impossible to dodge.
Fucking hell.
Envy.
Straight check.
Ah, this is the guy that makes smaller versions of himself, isn't it?
He's so tedious to fight.
Give me any other person to fight.
I can't hit anything.
Yeah, this guy is just not fun to fight.
It's just annoying.
Shwoop da boop!
I like that!
That's a good one!
In fact, it's huge.
Hold on.
Gotta eat all the rocks.
Of course.
I miss the heart.
Time for the boss.
I'm gonna shoop him.
Oh, yeah!
What?
The fucking stuff on the floor!
Man, I hate that mechanic.
I really hate that mechanic in this game.
Ah!
I got him.
What's that, a pony?
Speed, dash across the screen.
I think it's invulnerable and deals contact damage while dashing.
Rant's flight while held?
Oh, it's an active, I see.
Increase the speed to 1.5 while held.
If speed, stat is below that.
Invulnerable and deals contact damage while dashing.
I see.
Is it better than the shoop, though?
The shoop is kinda...
The fact that this gives me a lot of speed, though, like passively, is pretty good.
Oh, I'm riding the pony, look!
That is funny.
Okay.
But the shoop is where it's at, man.
It's gotta be the shoop.
Shoop is too good.
And the best part about the shoop is that it only has two energy bars.
Meaning I can use it pretty much all the time.
Curse of the unknown.
So what do I not know?
Right now.
Could be nothing.
Oh, I can eat these rocks, right?
Yeah!
What happens if I eat this?
Secrets open themselves.
Incredible.
And I take damage, good to know.
Eat them all.
I will blow this motherfucker up.
Thank you, Shurn.
Oh, curse of the unknown, meaning I can't see my HP.
That's probably what that is.
And I am doing no damage.
We eat all rocks here in this house.
Wow.
I was expecting there to be some items in these things.
But I guess not.
There we go!
Okay, so there are items in the pots.
It's just RNG.
I think I'm gonna go back here and open the shop.
We gotta go for the pill.
That was a hefty downgrade as well.
Very bad.
Alright, well.
Whatever.
Ma'am, you don't have any damage.
It really is... horrible.
Come on, more items.
Yeah!
Okay.
So the pots actually have a pretty high chance of containing something.
No treasure room yet, so we're not gonna go to boss.
This is the rule.
Also, cheers.
What does that mean on the right side with the heart?
Oh, maybe that's my current debuff, like Curse of the Unknown.
Probably what that is.
The purple one.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What is that?
That is a...
Yeah, I was about to say rotten tomato!
She has to fire special tears that apply a bait effect.
It slows enemies and draws them nearby.
Okay.
Well, I have minus one luck, so...
it will probably never happen.
I think it's time to go to the boss.
No, no, a couple of rooms more.
You never know what you're gonna find.
The way it pushes the bomb.
Wonderful.
I have a feeling.
Right here.
Really?
Okay.
But I have a secondary feeling as well in here.
Fuck me, dude.
How is anyone gonna dodge this shit?
There's too much shit on the screen, man!
Ugh!
That's frustrating to deal with.
I can't play!
Like, there's too much crap on my screen.
I hate that shit, man, with a passion!
Like, I can't keep track of ten fucking things at the same time.
So, whenever I encounter a room like that, it's just death.
There's nothing else to it.
There's also a tinted rock there.
Dead bird.
Uh, oh, that is the one that one of the other characters has.
When active chases and damages enemies for the current room.
Yep.
That is a really good item.
Glad I got that.
Thanks.
I just gotta pray that we don't find rooms with a bunch of fucking tears shooting everywhere.
Because it is frickin' impossible for me to deal with.
I can't do it.
This is a useless shot.
Nice.
Dammit.
Oh, you're still alive!
There you are.
Uh, okay.
Man.
For fuck's sake.
Thanks, bird.
I don't know what I would do without you.
Oof.
Uh, this guy, yeah.
Good thing I moved out of the way fast.
Jumping spiders are incredibly dangerous.
Still no bombs.
When I kite these around...
I'm stuck in a co- I can't move out of there.
Feels horrible.
Uh, we found a treasure room, you know what?
New plan.
We're going fast.
I'm super demotivated anyways.
Let's just fucking go.
Random bullshit strategies activate.
Ugh, my god.
I'm gonna die here.
Somehow I didn't.
Gimme that.
Move on, next.
We're speeding now.
Maximum speed.
Eight does a clock!
So maybe it's too late now.
If my theory about it is actually on point...
Let's try and find the boss.
There's a rock there, but I still have no bombs!
Just fantastic.
Uh, kill these guys.
Okay.
Thank you, bird!
What's that?
Oh, a random cart.
Oh, man.
We got the fool.
There's a pill in here too.
Yeah, but I have no bombs.
Nice choke point.
Man, the boss is nowhere near.
Crazy key.
Here it is.
We can also see time by doing this.
Four minutes and 35 seconds.
Maybe it's before five minutes.
I'm trying to be ultra fast here.
I can't, you know what, I kind of want to get hit so I can have the little bird spawn.
I actually did not get hit intentionally there, but I'm glad I did.
Special reward for me?
No?
Tropicamide.
Honestly, I'm not sure what's going on there.
The Emperor.
What was that one?
Teleports to boss room.
I'm already here.
Still no bombs.
Dude, what is going on here?
Like this run is pretty much over though.
Meaning to get the character unlocked, right?
Oh my god.
Now we got to try and go for the win, I guess.
Wait a minute, that was another place I wanted to use a bomb.
Down here-ish.
There.
Nice.
I don't know if that's more worth it though, or use it on the room here.
Actually, I should have used it here so I could have gotten those bombs.
What's that?
Fool.
Straight to boss room, I mean...
Okay.
I'll keep the boss room teleport.
Wait, now the timer's here!
The timer keeps moving!
Okay, now I'm confused.
Let's try and immediately go to boss room.
We're fighting Mega Man now.
Fuck me.
At least I have the bird now.
Oh my god!
Oh!
Gotcha!
Get him!
Nice.
Two rewards!
That could just be coincidence, but...
Moms, pearls...
I don't know what this is.
Transcendent tears.
Tears pass through walls and obstacles.
Tears that travel off the edge of the screen reappear at the opposite edge.
Whoa!
Okay.
Hello.
That's pretty good.
Yeah, look at this.
Oh, that's funny.
But they must have a lifetime.
Oh, I guess the lifetime is determined by the range.
Ah, I'm gonna go in here.
What is all this?
Guppy's tail?
What is that?
Sure, why not?
I have an immortal friend.
Following familiar, that blocks enemy shots, chance to deal instant room-wide damage each time it blocks a shot?
Could be good, I guess.
We haven't found the treasure room yet, though.
I wanna find that.
Man, this guy just won't die.
Nice.
I have a little bit of money.
Not exciting.
I gotta abuse the fact that this goes through rocks and stuff.
That is so good.
I'm lacking damage, though.
It's very obvious.
Oh my god, that was close.
Wait, what?
Oh, that triggered!
The little familiar triggered.
Cool.
A little too late, though.
Bro, what?
Where did you even come from?
Holy shit.
Oh, man.
My damage needs an upgrade!
Also, what was this stuff?
Random card.
Two of Clops.
What is that?
The bombs!
Ooh!
Sick!
That's kind of massive.
Hey, you know what, actually?
Let's see here.
Ah, no, I can't get in there, unfortunately.
What's this?
Toxic shock!
Mass poison!
Poison is all enemies at the start of each room.
Healing damage over time that scales with tear damage.
Destroyed enemies also leave behind a small creep pool that can damage other enemies.
What is it gonna damage me, though?
I really hope not.
Otherwise, this run is gonna end very soon.
Oh, he's not dead.
May as well use some bombs, right?
Not bad!
Solid performance there.
So we've already... Wait, what is that?
There's a special part in here.
Aha!
I missed it.
Okay, we did already get the treasure room, so maybe we just leave now.
Let's get out of here.
We're trying to go a little faster than usual.
Curse of the Unknown.
This is where I can't see my HP.
I only had one HP, though.
Wait, what?
Wow, the poison?!
The instant died!
That's incredible!
My whole screen is green, though.
Oh, shit!
Wow.
I think I'm at half HP right now.
This is not good.
Fuck!
Oh, wow.
It's probably over now.
The high priestess, what was that?
Oh, wait, that's the one with the mom foot, right?
Yep.
The high priestess.
Oh, wait, I should use this stuff.
Look.
Hahaha!
That's sick.
The fool.
Okay, if we're in a bad spot, I'm gonna leave.
This way.
I'm in a bad spot.
Wow.
I don't think I should enter that room.
That will kill me.
Look at this.
Hahaha!
Clever.
How am I not dead yet?
There's too much shit.
I thought they would be poisoned forever.
Looks like it's just a very short poison.
Money?
We could get some HP here.
Oh, okay.
Okay!
I mean, I don't need more keys at this point.
I have 12, you know?
Come on, just a single heart would make me happy.
I think I'm at a half HP right now.
More keys?
It's too much?
Anything but hearts, huh?
Okay, so that means...
Wait, how much HP do I have?
I must have more than one heart.
Because I definitely took, like, three hits.
I'm not sure, actually.
Unless I healed without realizing at some point.
Uh, we don't know where boss is.
You want bombs?
That's fantastic, brother!
I got bomb...
Okay.
Oh, thank you.
Here, that's for you.
Sweetness.
Nice.
More bombs for the bomb guy.
That gave me a demon points.
It is very demonic to do this, apparently.
That did not give me demon points.
So it's only demonic the first time you do it.
Come on, man.
Okay, well, I have this here if I need it.
I'm gonna save my last bomb.
Ah, they died.
Health up!
Huge!
I don't know if it heals me, though, so I'm gonna pick this up.
Good thing I did.
The Fool.
Fantastic.
Uh-oh, uh-oh.
Having range against these guys is super important.
That was a nice coin.
What is this?
Pupula duplex.
Spectral tears.
Wait, I already have spectral tears.
Right?
Increases tear size, giving them a wide shape.
Oh!
Cool.
I mean, does it really change anything?
I feel like it's the same as not having a bowl.
What's the point?
Oh, wait, I can also do this.
The Hierophant!
Soul!
Oh, my God.
Fantastic.
Now, this is problematic, though.
I can't get that chest.
Wait, I can, actually.
And maybe I should.
Rotten penny?
Why not?
Uh, I used the blue heart there, so I'm not gonna be able to heal.
Nice.
It's looking promising, though.
The husk.
Wow, how did I... That was totally luck.
So lucky.
Huh?
What the... Oh, spiders.
Fucking spiders.
Jesus juice!
We like the Jesus juice.
I'm gonna heal up.
Gimme this one.
And then we're gonna go do that challenge room.
Because usually there's a good reward there, right?
Ah,
it's closed.
Wait, wasn't that open earlier?
Hold on a minute.
So, we did something and then it closed.
I wonder what we did.
Could it be finding a treasure room?
Could it be, perhaps, defeating the boss?
That closed it, or maybe it was finding the secret room?
Could be one of those things.
So we must have done something in between.
Okay, that's interesting.
We're getting closer to an answer on that.
Yeah.
Man, I am really slow, though.
I gotta get some speed.
Let's go.
And now the timer's there.
Depth one.
Oh, fuck you, man!
Came out of nowhere!
So, this room is closed now.
I doubt it's gonna open.
Who knows?
I'm gonna save that heart.
Actually, I'm gonna go in here.
Oh, God.
Nice.
Thanks.
I've seen this room multiple times now.
What's coins?
I do have a lot of coins, but it's kind of risky being in there.
This is annoying.
Oh, I think I ran into the frickin' stone.
That's what happened.
Bro, he's just eating all my money.
Gimme an item, at least.
Ooh, dog!
Desert.
Ooh, that was worth it.
That was worth it.
Uh, yeah, let's not tangle with that.
Oh, shit.
What?
What's happening?
Oh, nice.
My familiar trigger.
Hell, yeah.
Very good.
What is this one?
Ooh, health down?
Yeah, no thanks.
I need more money.
Uh, let me also do this.
The hanged man...
flight for the room!
Very nice.
But where can we utilize it?
Oh, my God.
It didn't even hit them.
Because they're in their shitty shell.
Yeah, that's right.
Oh, you're gonna jump.
You're gonna jump.
Again!
This thing is very useful.
Saved my butt a couple times.
Oh, my God.
Ah, this guy again.
Uh, you're not getting my money.
I'm not getting my money, but this is good.
Load that up.
Epic.
Oh.
I've seen so many of those pills.
Okay, that guy died.
I think because he was all red.
Nice.
We have not found the treasure room, so we're going back.
Oh, careful.
There's an X here.
But I can't dig.
So, rip.
Wait, what?
That is not a ladder.
Is that...
I'm actually so confused.
Sad bombs.
Bombs fire 10 shots outward when exploding.
Oh, I see.
Sad because they're crying.
Crying tears.
I see.
I kind of want to try going in here.
Maybe after we defeat the boss.
Because there's a reward for defeating the boss.
And I intend to get that.
Wait, what am I doing?
It's this way.
Avoid that.
There's also an X in there, look.
Man, I wish I had a shovel.
Finding secrets.
Okay, here we go.
The gate.
That wasn't too bad, if I remember.
Ah, nice.
Kill the little guy.
Did he just kill his own guy?
It's amazing.
I'm ready for them to jump towards me.
Ah, shit.
Dude, that is so helpful.
Oh, my God.
That was a close one.
Honestly, that was...
Ah!
Fuck!
I thought we were done.
Jesus.
PJs.
Thanks.
Fuck me, I was so confused.
Okay, so wait.
I'm not going to go through that one.
I'll take the other one.
Because there's also a ladder over here, or not a ladder, more like a hole.
That's why I was hesitating, because there was not a clear ladder.
Is it down here?
Hey, look at this.
Is that just a random way to skip the boss?
Why don't you skip the boss, though?
You need the items.
I have 15 keys.
And lots of bombs.
Kind of worth it, I think, to use these bombs now with the shots that are being fired.
Shfired.
Do I...
I think I do exchange keeper bombs.
Because I have so many.
Me as well, right?
Fucking hell down again?
Is this the only pill that exists in this universe?
Like, what is happening to me?
We got the magician now.
Plus three range.
Oh, we also have flight if I need it.
What is damaging me?
Oh, you there.
Okay, okay, okay.
Lots of money.
I feel like I'm doing okay damage.
It's not the worst.
Two of diamonds.
Doubles, Isaac's coins!
Whoa!
Okay, we're going to wait with that until we have more.
That's crazy.
Mom?
She's still here.
There we go.
I mean, we have so many bombs.
Should we just start finding secrets?
Okay.
The fact that even the bombs projectiles fly across the screen and reappear on the other side, it's kind of cool.
So if we're in a small room and we put down a bomb, it's going to be crazy.
I'll use that here, I guess.
Shit.
Oh, that was a waste.
Guppy's collar!
50% chance to be revived?
Even more revival.
Nice.
Check this out.
Oh, it didn't even do anything.
Fuck, these guys coming back to life!
Nice.
This way.
Good.
A Bilgle cord.
Entering a room with half red heart or less, getting a little Steven familiar.
And then chance when taking damage to spawn a Gemini.
I mean, we're still unlucky.
But...
Yeah, I don't care about the rotten penny.
The rotten penny kind of sucks.
Shit, I mean, okay.
Wait, why is this guy a king?
Huh?
Look at that shit!
I've never seen that.
Dude, he's tanky as hell.
Wow!
Maybe that's what a champion is.
It's gotta be, right?
The hell is this?
Random buddy.
I got a familiar that fires tears with many randomized effects from other familiars.
Okay.
So random, holds up spork.
Or spoon or whatever it is.
That's an old one.
The lovers.
Spawns to red hearts.
Hey, look at my HP up there!
X2, question mark?
That's funny.
I wonder if Guppy is gonna trigger first in case I die.
And let's say Guppy is successful.
Does that save my...
you know, Lazarus revival?
Or is it the other way around?
That's a question for the ages.
We will never find the answer to that.
You know why?
Because I can't die.
Who am I kidding?
I die all the time today!
Fuck.
I'm so bad.
Get some bombs out there.
Holy shit!
Dude, that is actually such a good card with my setup.
Whoa!
Wait a minute, I had a better card somewhere.
Oh wait, I should bomb this.
No, I shouldn't.
Ah, this way.
Aha!
Wait, how do I even...
I can't get in there.
Can I be cheeky?
It's not enough!
Damn.
Ow!
I didn't mean to do that.
Like, it's impossible to kill these guys.
My familiars are doing the work here.
They're too fast.
Wow, what a room.
What's this?
Broken watch.
I think it's broken.
Every fourth room is slowed by 50%!
13% chance of speed.
Enemies up by...
Me no likey.
I'm gonna blow you up.
By the way, we did lose money in the donation machine.
We had 169, remember?
Confirmed now.
Fill it up again.
So it is like breaking the piggy bank a little bit when you do that stuff.
Okay, so they got slowed.
That's very helpful.
Fuck!
I was trying to push it.
Wait, we just lost demon points.
I don't understand these systems.
It makes absolutely no sense.
It feels so completely random.
Like, any random action I do, it's like, okay, here, you lose some points.
It's Mom!
I thought it wasn't time yet, but okay, here we are.
Yes, Mom?
What do you want, Mom?
I'm totally gonna revive here, hopefully twice.
Because there's no way I'm surviving.
When is that foot coming down?
There it is.
I need damage.
Bring me back.
Okay, I don't know which one did it.
It could have been Lazarus or the Guppy thing.
Fuck me.
Wait, what?
I think... I don't know.
I think this was Lazarus that happened.
Yeah, first it was Guppy and then it was Lazarus.
But, I mean, it's over.
Like, I can't even see what's happening on the screen, for fuck's sake.
I have four familiars and there's bullshit all over the screen.
It's impossible for me to dodge.
I'm just not made to dodge this shit.
I can't do it.
I don't have the skills to play this game, honestly.
There's too much shit on the screen for me.
I don't have six eyes, you know?
Go again.
A tooth?
Monstro's tooth.
The only way for me to win in this game is to be so incredibly broken that I don't care about projectiles.
Because if there's just too much on screen and I can't block it or I can't just out-damage it, I will die.
I don't have the skills to actually dodge the projectiles.
And that's just a fact.
And there's nothing I can do about it, it is just the way I am.
So the only way I can win is to become broken.
Let me see about how this works.
Someone's monster will slam down on a random enemy.
It's Isaac if no enemies are present.
I guess he just wants blood, huh?
Oh, that's interesting.
I think not.
Okay, not too bad.
Go hide in the corner.
Ah, shit!
Purple Heart!
Increase the chance of encountering champion enemies and bosses.
Chance for champions to drop their special loot.
Okay.
I think I've only seen the champion once, and that was last run.
Uh-oh.
Ah-ha!
Thanks.
Well, I... okay.
Completely useless.
Of course.
Uh, right.
Man, I can't hit this guy.
Fuck, he's annoying to fight.
Finally.
Ah!
Piss off!
Come on.
Ah!
That just killed me, honestly.
Shoot your shot.
Good.
Close one.
Soap.
Wait, I found this before.
Why is it question marked?
Bullshit!
I found this before.
I had this earlier.
It didn't get saved.
For some reason.
Why not?
Well, do items only save when you actually win?
Maybe that's what's happening.
I don't think that's the case, though.
Because I feel like I've seen items without winning that have been identified.
Like, even this right here is borderline too much for me.
With the amount of shit on the screen.
There's just too many projectiles.
The game has become get broken before the game breaks you.
You know?
If that had triggered this bomb, I may have been hit there.
God, it's so hard to hit.
Fuck me!
I haven't hit a single shot against him!
At least he's not immune to bombs.
Hey, what?
Ah, okay.
I'm playing it super safe.
I'm kidding.
Everything stays down?
Good.
I've got Jim on my side and a question mark.
What is that?
Let's Isaac throw a poison bomb?
I think the tooth may be better.
Yeah.
No enemies?
Stop spawning!
Get him out of here.
Come on.
Man, I'm so scared of that jumping spider.
He's not even the fast variety.
Where are you?
Finally.
I don't want to destroy that shit.
Takes too long.
It's my pin.
You like that?
I'm using the bosses against the bosses.
Oh, nice.
I got to keep moving against this guy.
Because if he pops out of the ground, I got to be ready.
There we go.
Another question mark.
A snack.
That's not too bad.
Another question mark?
Immortal.
Oh, that's the same guy I just had, isn't it?
Yeah.
Oh my God.
Mom.
That was lucky because I didn't even realize she was here.
I'm just moving on.
Take me to the next level.
Okay, so we don't know how much HP we have again.
Yeah, I feel like this is becoming more common.
Like, am I crazy?
Don't shoot there.
Come here.
Water room.
No fresh produce today.
Green man.
15 coins!
I need a shop.
I've seen this one before.
No, I haven't.
More eyes.
Each tier has a chance to fire additional shots in random...
Oh my God!
Look at the eyes of my character!
That's horrible!
Ugh!
That's disgusting, man.
Yikes.
Get smashed.
By the monstrosity.
I can buy a big old question mark.
Why not?
This one I've had before!
Bosses drop two items, only one can be chosen.
Okay.
Not enough to buy that pill, unfortunately.
Did I leave some HP behind?
Doesn't look like it.
We're going for the boss!
Mega fatty.
This guy is pretty tough.
So he jumps or something?
No, he pukes.
Great.
Okay, now he jumps.
Got it.
And now he pukes.
And we dodge.
He jumps.
Oh!
What's that?
Okay, that's that.
Fuck me, that was a fast jump!
Push!
Okay.
Wait, I can't pick the HP up?
Caffeine pill?
Spawns a random pill?
Or tiers and shot speeds?
I think I want more damage, I'm really lacking.
Yeah.
Especially because the more tiers are shoot, the more random tiers get spawned too, right?
I'm moving on, I'm leaving the rest of the level!
I'm getting impatient now!
A library!
What's that?
Book of Revelations!
Soulheart activating replaces the floor boss with a harbinger boss, if possible.
Passively increases devil and angel room chances.
I don't know what that means.
And this one was...
Summons a random familiar that lasts for the rest of the floor.
I want that.
Immediately.
What do we get?
This weird scarecrow?
Summons... wait, hold on, I need to see this again.
Activating replaces the floor...
I'm gonna try that.
Okay, it's been done.
I'm taking my tooth back.
Oh my god.
I'm getting good damage though.
I can't see what's happening!
Oh, shit.
I'm in trouble.
Maybe.
How has he not exploded yet?
Okay.
The left hand, I don't like that, I hate that actually.
Kill that green guy.
Jumps batteries.
Why not?
Smash him!
Take the battery again.
Run!
Oh my god.
Fuck!
That flying tomato is driving me crazy.
Wow.
I gotta stay at max HP, man.
Bye-bye.
Bodfly!
That's a good one, I like that.
We take that, of course.
We got some special enemies here.
I need some more HP.
What is this?
Is that like a laminated or a foil card or something?
One makes you larger.
One makes you small.
I don't know if I like that.
I'm gonna become an easier target.
At least I'll be able to see where my character is.
That's a big plus.
Like, bro, come on.
Calm down.
Wow.
I played a little risky there.
Man, why is my damage so bad?
I feel like I've got a lot of upgrades that should have made my damage good, but not the case.
Nice.
I mean, we're just going for it.
Pestilence.
That was actually incredible.
Oh,
I can't step in the green shit.
Well, not ideal.
The stapler.
I don't know why this is happening with the corners.
Why is everything becoming solid ground?
It's weird.
Or the cube of meat.
Uh, hmm.
I mean, I need damage.
I need that damage, bro.
Otherwise, we're not going anywhere.
Next level is Mom.
Not yet, not yet.
Oh, this is going to be trouble.
Very annoying enemies.
Did he just explode?
Is it worth it to try?
Yeah, why not?
The moon.
Oh, totally worth it.
Evil, evil fire.
It's gone.
Good.
Oh, this room looks horrible.
Wait, only some of them spawn spiders, or...
No, all of them do.
Oh, so if they die over empty space, the spiders won't spawn.
I want this.
Underwear.
Nice.
More range.
Oh my god, oh my god.
What the?
Yeah, that's good.
Do I like that more?
Encountering champion and...
Actually, I kind of want this.
I want to see what's up with that.
We need to figure it out.
This is some kind of Pisces, okay?
Tears up, knockback shot.
And tear size.
Not bad.
Oh, even faster attack speed.
That's one way to gain some DPS.
I feel like I'm still a little too slow.
That was actually a scary room.
You got a charge?
Yeah.
Man, man, man, man.
Look at the gravity.
Messing with my shots.
A shop?
What?
Ah, the fucking fire!
Ugh.
School bag.
Oh, that one sucks ass.
Because actives suck ass.
Mmm, I'll take a pill.
Pretty fly, I like that.
More flies, the better.
In fact, let me donate the rest, because I'm going to die any moment now.
Yeah, that's just...
I'm just glad there's space in this room for me to navigate.
Otherwise, I would have been dead.
Kill that ghost.
Oh, man.
Let's do it.
Mask of Infamy, okay.
That was a good amount of damage there.
Wait, what?
Oh, we can only hit him from behind, or...
I don't get it.
I'm dealing some damage?
Okay, now he died.
Ah, what do we want?
Damage in range, or...
Plus one health.
I think we gotta get the health.
There's no question.
We can't be running on 1 HP forever.
It's not sustainable.
Depths, too.
Jumping jacks.
Nice, I love that.
Put all these chests, though.
Like, what the hell is happening here?
It's like Schlaraffenland.
I have no keys?
What?
Why is it always like this?
Whenever there's a million chests?
I'll come back, I guess.
Mmm, up here.
Awesome.
You want hearts?
You can fuck off!
You're not getting my hearts.
It's too valuable to me.
Wait, what?
Oh, the fucking fly!
Stop spawning children.
Man, what a crazy room.
Who would've thought that poops could cause so much damage?
Love when that pops.
It brings me happiness.
That went better than I expected.
Box of spiders.
Like, give me a shoop or something.
Or how about a key?
Or ten?
Got him.
Jim!
Save me from this torment.
Like, that was pure luck that I didn't get hit there.
Doesn't help that my shots are the exact same color as everyone else's, you know?
What now?
I guess there's only one way.
Okay.
I think... what is it that's blocking all these projectiles?
I can't get to him.
Pop up.
I wonder if that hits them when they're in the floor.
Ah!
There we go.
That hit them for sure.
What the heck is this?
I've never seen that.
Put a bomb here.
Fuck yeah, man!
Gamble.
I feel asleep?
Come on.
Just Lazarus things.
Hashtag.
Born unlucky.
That didn't even do anything!
Easy.
Boom.
Boss time.
In fact, it's Mom.
Uh, Monstro, what the fuck are you doing?
You were supposed to hit Mom.
You missed the mark completely.
What the hell?
There it is.
Wow!
Wow, that was close!
Give me that.
Placenta.
Bro!
It's too close!
Man, that sea is actually kind of amazing right now.
Even though it's cold.
What the fuck?
Oh, hell yeah.
You chained up, Arya!
Too bad.
Oh!
Yes!
Oh, that didn't do a lot, did it?
It's best against a lot of small ones, I guess.
Good.
Ooh!
These guys are kind of tough.
Oh, not this guy.
We should definitely set a trap here.
Wait, there's more?
Where?
Oh.
Okay.
Problem is, I don't know how much HP I have.
It seems to be every other level now, for some reason.
I'm getting very unlucky with that.
I don't know how...
How am I dying?
I don't even understand how I'm dying.
I don't understand what is happening.
It makes no sense.
Makes no sense to me at all.
Let's play the only character that is actually able to beat this game.
I am so tilted of just dying to shit I can't even see.
It's so annoying.
Like, why would you ever play any other character?
What is the point?
This guy is so much better than everything else.
Is that a lemon?
Wait a minute, it's an active lemon.
Creates a small pool of damaging yellow creep.
What lasts for the...
So that's what the lemon mishap is all about.
Man, the range is shit right now.
Okay.
Nothing up there.
I gotta get used to the fact that the charge is so slow at first.
Just speedrun this right now.
Ow.
Ho ho.
Thanks.
That's for you.
The lemon mishap.
Go on.
Famine.
Give me that.
Nah, I'm good.
At least we did this fast.
Maybe there's something about the timer now.
Wait, what the hell is this all?
The overlay made it seem like this room was like broken in half.
Hard to explain.
But on the minimap I mean.
Right.
Okay.
Cool.
Thanks.
Bump friend.
Just like that hanging out.
Isn't that kind of weird?
Give me that.
Whatever.
There were no spikes on that one.
I don't understand why there were spikes on it when I hit it.
Give me those.
We're speedrunning this shit now.
We just gotta get back to mom.
Mom is the only place where we feel safe.
She's the only one who can protect us.
Mom is not that bad, actually.
I mean, she's our mom, right?
She loves us.
Everything she does is because she loves us.
Come here.
What are you doing over there, huh?
Not allowed.
You're gonna die.
Everyone dies.
Are there more?
There you are.
That should do it.
No drops for me.
I got 11 coins?
What is that?
I feel like I've had this one before.
But it's not revealed.
Did that just remove the coin over here?
I don't get it.
Head of the keeper.
Cheers that hit enemies have a 5% chance to...
Sure.
I don't know what's happening right now.
I am just accepting.
Whatever comes my way here.
Pill, we always eat those.
Fantastic.
Not there.
Fuck me, dude.
I'm too fast for my own good.
I just flew straight into them.
Blighted ovum.
What is an ovum?
Kind of body part, I imagine.
Please charge it.
Pageant boy!
Random coins.
What's that one?
Oh, it's a flat penny.
Wait, what?
Chance to spawn a key is time you pick up a coin.
Chance is increased with nickels and dimes.
Okay.
Yeah.
It's not looking too good.
I was hoping for a health upgrade.
Speed.
Speed mode, go.
Gimme, gimme, gimme.
What's that?
How to jump?
Wow.
I mean, I love getting that on this character every single time.
Very, very important.
I do have 17 coins.
This one sucks.
I will take that one.
I will take a pill.
Luck.
Fantastic.
One luck.
Uh, what?
Duct tape.
Huh?
I mean, at least it will stick in there real...
Oh!
Uh...
I don't like that.
Why is that a good thing?
I guess it would be fantastic if you're doing the solar system.
Imagine that.
Huh?
That was the big drawback of that.
You know, having to wait for it to rotate.
Uh, do we go?
We go.
The Duke of Flies is nothing.
Hey, we're gonna take care of fast.
I mean, look at this.
Yay!
We got healing.
Fantastic.
And now you want to take my health away?
It better be good, then.
More damage or...
Random pick.
That's a lot of extra damage, though.
That's...
That's a lot of extra damage.
I need it.
Yep.
I feel like that may be worth it.
Like, that is legitimately so much more extra damage.
Alright.
Lock in now.
Lock the F in.
No mistakes.
Bomb that.
Dang it.
Keep moving.
Get blasted, man.
Uh-oh.
How am I gonna do this?
That's how we do it.
Come from the side.
Tactical, strategic.
That was a great decision.
That was a sub-optimal decision.
Give me this.
The pickaxe.
You gotta pick the coins up immediately when you destroy the flames.
Otherwise, they will disappear.
Well, that's not good.
I'm in danger.
We're gonna wait for these guys to synchronize.
There we go.
If I wasn't Azazel right now, I would be dead in this room.
Wait, there's a treasure room.
What the fuck?
Let's go get that.
Oh, wait a minute!
This is something we unlocked in a cutscene!
Rubber cement.
Bouncing tears.
Tears bounce off of enemies and obstacles.
Does it?
Maybe not with this attack.
Actually, yeah, it does look like it.
But is that good?
I feel like that would be better with normal tears.
Unless I get something that makes this sort of shoot at an angle.
Where I can really take advantage of that.
By the way, why is there a little... You see this here?
It's almost like I need to dig here or something.
You see the lines?
Alright, Gertie.
This is gonna be a rough one.
I forgot what you do.
I need to see what you do.
Man, fuck you!
Unbelievable behavior from that guy.
Like, I was waiting ten years for him to show him what he did.
And as soon as I go for attack, then he fucking runs into me.
At light speed.
Does it get more unlucky than that?
I don't think so.
Wait, I can't see my HP now.
Ah, go in here.
Honestly, whatever.
A bunch of bullshit is... green is probably good.
I don't have the patience for that right now.
Move on.
Ah, go!
We're going.
Watch this.
Holy fucking shit.
Go!
We're speedrunning.
We need to go even faster.
It's not fast enough.
Let me in.
Gimme, gimme, gimme.
Thanks.
See you later.
Yep.
Go, go, go.
Go!
Watch this.
Ghost pepper.
Butcholokia.
Chance to fire a spectral flame projectile in place of a tear?
Flame projectiles deal heavy damage to enemies and block enemy shots.
Whoa, okay.
Neat.
It's kind of cool.
Move on.
Drive by.
I mean, look at this.
How can any character compete with that?
I'll take this.
Magashurn.
I got eight.
Wax.
Ex-lax.
Oh, wait.
The coins didn't disappear.
Okay, we got the treasure room.
We're getting lucky with the hearts here.
Speed, speed, speed, speed, speed.
That was insane.
The sprinkler has appeared, okay.
More health.
I mean, we have luck on our side.
Fast, fast, fast, fast.
Samson.
Hey, new character!
Fuck yeah.
I got no keys.
Rip.
Don't even think about it.
I'm just cleaning house with this laser here.
Give me that.
Wait, did I miss another one in there?
I think I missed another heart.
Unless it just didn't update fast enough after I picked it up.
Oh, okay, okay.
I thought it was a blue heart.
Insane.
Great luck.
No keys, though.
Gotta find those.
Shit.
We got plenty of bombs.
Maybe we can find some tinted rocks.
There we go.
We got a key.
You're not taking my key.
We gotta go to the treasure room now.
Mom's razor?
I can re-roll it?
The Ludovico technique.
Here's transform into a single...
How does that work on this character?
That's minus damage, though.
What the fuck, bro?
Let's fucking go!
That is sick.
Look how thick that is.
It's a thick boy.
What?
Insanity.
The Ludovico technique.
Wow!
Damn!
I don't know what that did.
Safety cap.
Chance of finding a pill.
And additional pill and chests.
Okay, okay.
Well, we're just going straight in here.
Well, we got the circle of death.
Hopefully that should be good enough.
Bye-bye.
I mean, look at that.
It's crazy.
And... moving on.
Getting lucky with the upgrades.
I mean, this is what I mean.
We gotta get broken.
That way we can win.
Curse of the mace?
Wait, I've not seen that one.
Oh, that was a pill.
Got some flies.
The devil deals damage, right?
No!
Wait, why are there enemies in here again?
Didn't I just clear this room?
I'm actually kind of confused.
Oh, wait!
Is that what the mace is?
Things shift randomly?
Hide in the corner, use the Ludovico technique.
Take him
out.
We have not found the treasure room.
I gotta find that first, though.
That's a must.
There it is.
The wiz.
I think it fires two tears.
Brother!
Spectral tears.
Is this gonna do anything for me?
I don't think it changes anything.
Alright, boss time.
Fistula!
Holy fucking shit.
Unless those two tears are contained within the circle.
Torn photo.
Thanks.
Here's the thing.
Yeah, we're leaving.
No curse.
Good.
I can't not think of the NASA missions when I hear that.
Gemini missions.
I don't know what the rainbow does.
The rainbow apparently just rainbows.
And maybe it's good.
Nobody knows.
I want this room.
Oh my god.
You know what, you can have the coin.
I don't want it.
Puberty.
Puberty!
That one is also kind of a mystery.
I feel like I need to find the same pill again so I can read the description when it's on the floor.
That's when I will actually figure out what puberty does.
Dude, the durovico technique is just a whole different technique.
It's unstoppable.
Shaolin.
This one's on sale.
Sick.
What do I want?
What is that even?
Fifteen?
I can maybe have it.
I cannot have it.
But perhaps I can have it in a second.
Yeah, let's go.
The blokes, that's a new one.
What are you gonna do?
Oh wait, I've seen this guy before.
I mean, okay.
Just keep the circle on him and you win.
Oh, look at this.
Angel room.
The holy mantle, this is a great one.
There's no way we can fail now.
Like, this is pretty much just done and dusted at this point.
This is gonna be a cakewalk.
There is no chance in hell that I can lose this now.
I'm just too broken.
Nice.
Great.
A pill?
Okay, sure.
I'm gonna save this card until the last boss.
I mean, look at this, man.
Look, it's crazy.
Tears.
Jesus Christ.
We could fight mom immediately or we can find the extra item.
I want the extra item.
This way.
We should also heal down here.
Sponsor portal of slippery creep.
Slippery creep, okay.
So when enemies walk on that, they're gonna fall over, I guess.
Maybe get, what do you call it, knocked down or something.
What's this?
Chaos.
Want some pickups, all item pedestals, draw from random items.
Sure.
Oh, shit.
Yeah.
Oh, that's a...
Oh, I broke my thing, no!
Fuck.
Well, that's annoying.
Give me that one.
Let me see what this is.
Justice.
May your future become...
I don't think I like that.
Nah.
I'll keep the devil, thank you.
There's no I'm getting balanced when I'm broken.
Okay.
Where is this item room?
Uh, okay.
You know what, I could go in there.
Because I have this thing on.
And the way to do this is to blow it up.
Pills!
Okay, that I don't know what is.
We love that one.
I'm just smashing everything right now.
With an area here.
Challenge room is closed.
For reasons unknown.
Whoa!
Fanny pack!
She has to drop a pickup when taking damage.
Hey!
Okay, just like that.
Isn't that kind of crazy?
Uh oh.
I mean, that's, yep.
Candle!
This is something I unlocked.
Curse immunity plus evil up.
Curse immunity!
That sounds really good.
Immunity to floor curses, immunity to negative effects from certain items.
Wow, increases chance of encountering devil or angel.
That sounds like an insane item.
Gym.
I don't care about the arcade.
Actually, I want to go in there and just have a look.
I'm going to blow everything up.
Amazing.
Uh, a super magnet.
What do I have now?
Finding pills?
No, I like the pills.
We can fly, so it doesn't matter.
One thing I want to do, though.
Go back to the shop.
And, what was this pill?
Why not?
Oh, no, wait.
I think I may want...
Oh, soul hearts.
Yeah!
That one.
Fantastic.
And we can take this.
I'm going to bomb you.
Because why not?
We just gained more on demon and angel.
Okay.
Alright, this one should be a cakewalk now.
What the fuck, man?
Look at that damage just disappeared.
Or health.
Should I be sitting in a corner?
I wonder if this is a good idea.
Just sit over here.
Can her feet hit me over here?
Okay, they can.
As expected.
What is that?
Bob's brain.
Explosive thoughts.
Immediately, the charge is in the direction Isaac is firing.
Explosion applies poison.
Oh, wow.
There are so many items.
Lucky foot!
Hey!
That's a good synergy with my pill collections.
Where's your going to speed through this now?
Speed mode.
There was this room.
Wait, what?
Oh, he's going to activate the...
Wait, what the...
Those enemies are so weird.
Speed rod, speed rod.
Faster, faster.
We cannot enter here.
Oh, wait, there's more?
Oh, you.
Oh, whoa!
It's open!
Sick!
We got a mushroom.
Tears up.
A mind-changing experience.
There's more.
No problem.
I will say, though, it feels like my damage is a little low.
But it's not bad, you know?
It's just low, it's not bad.
Puberty, taking three gives the adult transformation and plus one health.
Aha!
So that's what puberty does.
Got it.
Experimental pill.
Fantastic.
That is incredible.
I didn't mean to do that.
It just happened.
Mmm, this way.
Wow, I actually went in the complete wrong direction.
Friends till the end.
Hold on, I need to see what it does.
Spawns three will fly.
Okay, okay.
Some of the items are voiced over.
Some are not.
And it feels random as well.
Like, sometimes the same item will not be voiced over.
Tears up.
Nice.
How about damage up?
But I guess tears up is kind of damage up for me.
Something's wrong.
Oh, I have two of these now?
No need for that.
Mom's foot.
Wait, what is the other one?
I can't see shit.
Yeah, I guess that's good.
Yo, wait a minute.
I kind of want to try...
Mom's foot against Mom's heart.
Maybe there's a special combo there.
Last time I used the Bible, and she just freaking died.
So who knows what's happening?
What do I get?
A smaller chest.
Oh!
Oh, yeah?
Uh, where can you see?
Oh, here?
Oh!
Strength.
That's a good one.
I'm gonna keep that.
Bad gas.
Fart dealing five damage and poison nearby enemies.
Uh, recharge one.
Oh, thanks.
The Ludovico technique.
It's like shadow boxing.
If it's properly wielded, it's almost invincible.
The Wu-Tang style.
Wait, uh, safety cap.
Yeah, okay, that's fine.
The butt people.
Wait, what?
I thought it was mom time!
Uh, fake mom?
No, wait, uh, the pact.
Damaged to- ooh.
That's good.
Dude, I have so much HP, there's no way I can lose.
Oh, we even got the extra heart from the freaking eternal heart.
Uh, what is the cap doing?
Rants tears up on a slight speed down, but causes the screen and sounds to become slightly distorted.
Okay, I guess mushrooms.
This affects stacks with multiple activations, granting more stats and making everything increasingly distorted.
That is actually kind of funny.
Oh, what the hell is that?
I've never seen that enemy before.
Oh my god, look at all these pills.
Bad guess.
I don't want to use those pills during combat.
Give me that.
Emothesis?
Emotemesis.
Okay, that's how you say that.
Yes, yes.
I think we can fly over that.
This is kind of a big-ass floor, isn't it?
Like, what the hell?
There's so many rooms!
Whoa!
Damn, son!
Ludo Vico!
Ain't messing around.
Oh, how am I taking damage?
Oh, I'm not.
The enemies are.
I could go in there now, but we haven't gotten our upgrade yet.
Activate this.
Oh!
Oh, shit, bro!
What the fuck?
Okay, we're high as fuck.
Again.
Oh, yeah.
Stack that up.
Friends till the end.
Keep going, brother.
Keep getting more and more fucking high.
Oh, this is the perfect weapon to have against this.
I hate this enemy, so this is great.
We gotta swoop the loop!
But honestly, I want to keep getting high.
Even more high.
Keep getting high.
Whoa!
Whoa, brother!
Consul.
I have to take damage sometimes.
Familiar.
Almost the other one.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah, we gotta keep taking pills here.
I mean, there's no reason not to.
Whoa.
More pills.
Holy shit.
Whoa.
Dude, I'm high as fuck.
What the?
Whoa, what is this?
Free lemonade.
Party time?
Spawn a large pool of damaging yellow cre- okay.
Honestly, that's not bad either, but...
What's this?
Lost fly?
Lost protector.
Cool.
What's this?
Can I refresh these?
I can't see shit.
Get that circle out of the way.
I need to go deeper!
Yo, let's go dig.
Wait a minute, what if we dig here?
Huh?
Dude!
Where are we going?
Whoa!
Whoa, what's happening?
What the fuck?
Shill?
Uh...
This is freakin' hell or something.
All right, all right.
Open all the chests.
I'm high as fuck.
We all know what's happening.
Noodle Vico, go!
I can't see shit.
Okay.
Wow, he's tanky.
He's really tanky.
Tanky boy.
More pills.
Dude, I am so lucky for luck right now.
Oh, okay, my pill wore off.
What the hell, man?
Music too is super weird.
Nice.
What is going on?
Where's the guy I need to kill?
Oh, there he is.
He's not revealing himself!
The hermit.
Teleport to the stew.
Yes.
I'm rich.
The shop is empty?
Wait a minute, something's off.
Okay, I don't get that.
I guess there's no shop in hell.
Unidentified, man.
Oh, okay.
I almost can't see where I am because of my stupid circle.
I don't even know what I'm fighting.
I just bring the circle on the creature, and the creature dies.
It's awesome.
Woah!
Oh, man, I'm scared.
I'm so scared.
Oh, I shouldn't have done that.
Uh, blow him up.
Blow him up.
Gimme.
Oh, that's underwhelming.
Distant admiration.
Distant orbital, the fly that deals contact.
What's that?
Oh, it's my fly.
More pills.
Man, my tears are just going up and up and up, but apparently it's not going up.
I feel like there was no stat increase.
The wafer.
Yo!
That's a crazy one.
That is insanity, bro.
What the fuck?
Lard.
Less speed.
Yeah, that's fine.
That is incredible, actually.
Am I just finding crazy upgrades all over the place?
How nuts is that?
Look at this.
More tears, but it's not affecting anything.
It doesn't... yeah, there's a limit, it seems, to how many tears I can have.
Okay.
There's a boss here.
What is that boss going to be, though?
Is it going to be Mom or something else?
What the hell, man?
What if we keep digging?
What if we say no to that?
We just go!
Dude.
Hold on, I'm not done clearing.
Actually, what I'm going to do, I'm going to go in the boss room.
Fight whatever is there.
When I win, I'm going to dig.
Down, down, right?
All the way to the end.
Wait, there's a heart in here.
Wait, I can't take it?
Do I have too many hearts?
I can't get more tears, I can't get more hearts.
I'm too strong!
Satan!
Yo!
Wait, what?
Oh, it's like...
oh.
Okay, here we go.
Satan, you ain't shit.
Uh-oh.
Oh, God.
Yeah, Satan, you're done.
You're done.
Wait, you're not done yet.
Uh-oh.
Wow.
Oh, my God, I don't even know what's happening.
Okay!
Guys, I am not going to open this.
It didn't work!
I can't dig!
Oh, my God!
I can't go deeper!
Here we go!
We are... wait a minute.
I think I just realized something.
Or maybe that was the reveal of that realization.
I was wondering why the UI always kept saying, increases Isaac's tears and whatever, when we're clearly not playing Isaac.
But it's just Isaac in costume.
He's pretending to be someone else.
He's fronting.
It's like he has multiple personalities.
That makes so much sense, actually.
The demon tail has appeared.
Ooh, you unlocked Judas?
Wait a minute.
What?
Look at the file?
Why does it look like that?
Huh?
It's a smiley.
Or a map, or something.
Wait a minute.
I also unlocked something else.
Bloodlust.
Judas.
Oh, it's a character!
Book of Belial?
That's a demon!
Jacob.
Did I unlock something else?
Judas?
Wait, one HP.
Four damage!
Is that the most damage so far?
No, Azazel is four, of course.
Azazel is amazing.
Book of Belial.
This is definitely...
a follower of the demonic stuff.
Magdalene?
Oh my gosh.
Hold on a minute.
I need to see something.
Stats?
Items.
I need to see how many I've... Holy shit, I found a lot here.
Wow, there's a lot of items.
What?
How?
Wait, how do you... How is there so many items?
Holy shit, I thought I was definitely like...
I don't know, like 70% through the items.
Simply because I kept finding the same items.
Dude, wait, secrets.
Oh, neat.
Oh, that's nice.
I can look at this again.
You unlock the womb.
The harbingers.
Oh, these are the guys on horses, I see.
Cube of meat.
It's an item, I guess.
Dude, that...
And actually getting to a new level was crazy.
I honestly thought it wouldn't work.
Because I thought mom's heart was like...
That's it, you know?
We're done.
So I thought maybe digging wouldn't work or something.
The fact that there was a hole when I did it...
Got me so excited.
And I jumped in and it was like a whole new place.
Bro...
Unfortunately, we can't keep digging after that.
What happened at the end when I tried to dig was what I expected to happen when I dig or dug the first time...
In mom's place.
You know?
That also says something.
So if we dig deeper into mom's soul...
If we dig into her heart...
We arrive...
In hell.
She is possessed...
By a demon.
She's obviously controlled by Satan.
Satan was controlling her heart, right?
That's why she's an evil piece of shit.
Who serves us dog food.
Hits us with the belt or whatever, right?
With the spoon.
Tries to get an abortion with a coat hanger.
Failed obviously since we're here.
Like she is evil itself.
And she needs to be eradicated.
Um...
Hold on a minute.
What's up with these red ones?
Aper... Wait.
Is that something for today?
Cellar one.
I'm icing I guess.
Uh oh.
Yeah blow them up, blow them up.
That's fantastic.
Want to make sure larger?
Wait, did...
Is that the joke I got smaller instead?
Because I'm not large, I'm very tiny.
Okay.
I thought maybe everything was free today.
Oh, we got one here.
Amazing.
Wait, April spools.
I wonder if this is something for today.
Or was it yesterday?
Yeah, today is the second of April.
But like...
Or maybe it's like an archived challenge from years ago or something.
Oh god.
The bloat.
Maybe the bosses have been changed.
Honestly couldn't tell you.
I don't know if this is normal.
Wait, why is my...
Fuck is going on?
My heart was golden.
And I guess when I got destroyed, it spawned a bunch of gold.
That's what happens.
This boss is crazy difficult.
These things have a million HP.
Oh my god.
Okay, we finally got the small ones.
Why do I keep taking damage?
Oh!
Okay.
Oh well.
I had to try that.
That was kind of funny.
Okay.
Man, I did not expect to actually play for four and a half hours.
I was planning on making this a three hour stream.
But I got too far into the tilt hole and I needed to get a win.
So I couldn't stop playing.
You know how it is.
It got personal at the end.
And boy did we win.
Dude,
I got so tilted halfway through this, it's crazy.
And it made it worse as well because I started doing shit decisions going weird places.
It didn't make any sense.
That was a catastrophe for sure.
Are you feeling better after that run?
I feel like I'm on the moon.
Okay?
Maybe this is what an abusive relationship with my mother feels like.
You know?
Like you want to leave her, but you can't.
Because she loves me.
She beats me up all the time, but you know, we love each other.
Do you feel like you deserve that win?
Of course.
I found all the good items.
So obviously I deserve to win.
Are you also the type of guy that says you can only play Dark Souls naked with a two hander and no upgrades?
Come on, man.
What's your favorite game ever?
World of Warcraft.
Classic.
I know about that more, but it's just insanely hard to see.
Like putting red stuff on a red floor.
When there's a million things on screen, I'm not good with that.
Like I'm not good at dodging that in that case.
I'm trying to dodge projectiles, figure out where my actual character is.
With five familiars around me and ten million enemies.
It's really difficult.
How long will you continue this series until I found all the items?
Maybe.
I need more items.
More items.
Or maybe not all items, but most items.
Did you enjoy getting high?
I did, it was fantastic.
I can't believe we reached some kind of cap on hearts.
Like, whoa.
Insanity.
Satan was easy.
Like, come on, what is this even?
Yeah.
Easiest boss in the game.
Not even close.
You know who's harder?
The freaking guy who pops into smaller versions of himself.
I was gonna give up on my sack, but then I got high.
Yeah.
I wasn't gonna give up, though.
Honestly, if anything, it's just getting more personal.
And I start tilting a little bit, but that's okay, it happens.
The game is just knowledge and a little bit skill.
Well, you just described how a game works.
You're correct.
That's how games work, yes.
The more you know and the more better you get, the more better.
But yeah, the better you get, of course you're gonna get better at the game, right?
I know about that.
It is a hard game.
It's a tough one.
Like, if I compare this to something like Hades, Hades 1 at least, this one is way harder.
But honestly, it's only because of the way the game is made graphically for me.
Like, I'm just having trouble with all this stuff on the screen.
I feel like Hades was way more clear.
You know, like, much better telegraphed on what was happening on my screen.
Oliver, can you scream like the video yesterday?
No, I can't.
I need a genuine fright to scream like that.
If you wanna see me scream, you should watch Amnesia The Bunker, okay?
I screamed plenty in that one.
I can't scream on command, I'm sorry.
Bible left ear, Satan right ear.
That's honestly what was going on in that video.
Satan was chasing me, and then we had a Bible on the left.
Have you been catching up the Artemis 2 mission?
Of course!
Dude, I was up late, so late last night.
Because it was at a shit time for me, you know, but I had to see it.
And I watched it so late into the night until I just fell asleep.
Because I couldn't stay up all night.
And then for some reason, I woke up super early, so now I'm actually kinda tired.
Maybe that's one of the reasons why I also got a little tilted, or something.
Maybe that's just an excuse, but I am tired today.
I did not get enough sleep.
I was so happy to see that launch be successful.
Like, I was so afraid something would go wrong, and...
Everyone would die, and, you know, space flight would be set back 50 years because of that.
I don't know.
I was so relieved, as soon as they got up into space.
When are you going to space?
When I become rich enough to pay for it?
I would do it, man.
I would love to go to space.
I think I need to do some more... or spend some more time in the gym, though, before doing it.
It's apparently pretty taxing on your body.
Ludo Vico the tilt negator, yes!
For sure.
Will you stream in space?
Dude, it's already hard as it is to get images back to Earth live.
I think it's going to be a problem.
If Katy Perry can make it, I'm sure you can, too.
Wait, she went to space?
Did she go on one of those commercial things?
I didn't realize that.
Did she actually go, like, into orbit, or is it just, like, suborbital?
Like, I'm not actually sure, I'm not really following the commercial spaceflight stuff.
On the base?
Okay, so suborbital?
Okay, I mean, that is space, but, yeah.
Ludo Vico, favorite item?
You know what, actually?
I don't think so.
I think I like the item more, that makes me go laser infinite.
The infinite laser?
Turn me into Lazarus, or turn me into Azazel when I'm not Azazel, and I'm having a good time.
Yes, Brimstone, that one.
Man, when I had that, I was having the time of my life.
Just having that infinite laser is incredible.
It's still a little bit weird to have a disconnected sort of movement of the character and movement of the Ludo Vico.
Especially when a circle is so big and bright and thick that I can't even see what's happening on screen a lot of the time.
It's covering up my character and items and stuff like that, you know?
But it's still fun, like Ludo Vico is fantastic.
But, yeah.
Give me Azazel minus the Azazel, exactly.
Yeah, give me Flying and Brimstone and I'm on the moon.
If Brimstone is so good, how come they haven't made a Brimstone 2?
Good question.
Sequels are always bad.
Maybe that's what they realized, you know?
Stick to the original.
All roads lead to... Yeah!
It was so funny that day when that happened, because I kept getting upgrades that would turn me into Azazel.
When I was intentionally trying not to play Azazel.
No spoilers, please, Svarios.
If you can help it.
If you do spoil, you're probably gonna get muted.
Best case, I'm just not gonna read your message, if it seems like it's a spoiler.
What's my favorite artist band?
I don't know.
That's a good question.
I mean, based on pure listening time, since I was young, it's gotta be Eminem, I think.
I have just listened to his album so much since I was a small kid.
So based on that, probably Eminem.
Favorite song is probably Sing For The Moment.
Man, I love that song.
I also really like Linkin Park.
I haven't really listened to Linkin Park a lot, though.
A little bit more recently, because they came out with a whole new album, right?
Which was actually a banger.
But other than that, I really enjoy, like, old-school rap, you know?
Gangster rap.
I like that a lot.
If you've seen Office Space, you know, with the nerdy kid in the car, sing along, that's me.
If that gives you some idea.
Did Eminem help with learning English?
It definitely helped me swear more.
And I do attribute some of that to Eminem, the fact that I'm swearing so much.
Because it was cool to swear, you know?
Because Eminem did it.
I'm new here.
I just checked Vox.
How is his Majora's Mask so beautiful?
I don't know.
It's just this.
Any dinner ideas?
Oh, actually, I haven't thought about that.
What do I even have right now?
I think it's just going to be a classic Danish whoopla smell.
Rye bread with some toppings.
I have some salmon.
I got some cottage cheese.
I also have some fish.
Fregidels.
I don't know what you would call that in English.
Fishballs, I think?
Some remoulade on top, you know?
Some lemon.
Oof.
Yeah.
That's good.
Fishballs.
I mean, not fishballs, but, you know, like...
I don't know what the word is.
It's good, though.
Trust me.
I did not watch the Parlor Room compilation.
I mean, I was there.
I saw it myself in first person, you know?
But...
Yeah.
I did give it a like, though.
Maybe I'll watch it at some point.
I think it'll be more fun to watch when I have sort of forgotten what I did.
And the stuff I said.
Did
you like the video yesterday?
My April Fools.
I actually went ahead and did it, by the way, guys.
We talked about the Chinese Bible in the left ear and something else in the right.
I actually sat down and did it.
It's on the channel now, if you haven't seen it.
It's so stupid.
Dude, when I was editing that, I was just laughing constantly.
Because I kept hearing this Chinese guy in my left ear, and I kept thinking, what am I doing?
Why am I making this?
It is so dumb.
Did you start watching Amnesia?
Good.
That game is fantastic.
I recommend it.
Even though it killed me.
It is actually a fantastic game.
Hey, Atlanta, I was watching the Artemis launch.
I stayed up late for it, too.
It was fantastic.
Something I was looking forward to for a while.
And also, I was scared of it, you know?
Because if things went wrong and all that.
I know that keeps sending people up to the space station all the time, of course.
But I feel like a mission to the moon, you know?
That one is something special.
I mean...
Man, are we actually going to see people landing on the moon in our lifetimes, you know?
Because that's something I really envied, of the older generations, in 1969.
Imagine seeing that stuff on TV, you know?
Maybe in 10 years or so, maybe less, we get to see actual humans land on the moon again.
Oh!
That's going to be so hype!
I know this sounds nuts, but if your ripe bread is similar to the Finnish kind, try toasting it and then putting peanut butter and strawberry jam on it.
I mean, that's just called a...
That's a PB&J, right?
Except without the toast.
We do actually toast our ripe bread here, too.
I haven't tried that with peanut butter and jam, though.
I'll give it a shot.
It sounds pretty good.
It does not sound nuts at all.
Actually, it does, because it's nuts.
Maybe that was the point.
But it sounds good on ripe bread, actually, if it's toasted.
It even sounds good on normal ripe bread, on toasted.
It sounds like nuts, but peanuts are actually legumes.
I have no idea what legumes are, or legumes.
I don't know how to pronounce it.
This is some weird type of... not nut, but something else.
How do you like the games, OST?
I love the games, OST, but here's what's funny.
Nowadays, when I'm playing this game, I don't even hear the music half the time.
I'm so focused on the gameplay.
Like, it's like I tune it out.
Because I've heard the tracks so much now, right?
Because it's the same tracks.
The good news is, it's not bad music, otherwise it would be bothering me, I think.
But the fact that I'm able to tune it out, you know...
I suggest slowing down a bit.
I will go even faster now.
Next time, I'm doing only speedruns.
I'm not even going to care about anything other than my time.
I'm going to get a speedrun overlay and everything with the green numbers, stages, I'm going in.
Speedrun all items in the game.
No sleep challenge.
You return to T-Boy, because no!
Don't eat the crack!
How long have you been sober, Donaldo?
I can't believe I've done this.
I mean, how else do you pronounce it?
Do you say T-B-O-I?
That's too long.
T-Boy.
Right?
A year?
Oh, man.
You should have, like, a sponsor, you know?
You call up.
Hey, man, listen.
I know it's late, but I'm having urges.
I just saw the streamer play this...
We don't need to talk about that.
We all know what it is.
And I have the game booted, and I'm almost clicking new game.
Help me.
T-Boy.
T-B-O-I.
I say T-Boy.
Okay, well... T-Boy.
It's a horrible acronym.
It's not good at all.
If only it was Binding of Isaac, and not THE Binding of Isaac.
Just having it be Boy would be so much better.
There's also a meme with that, with the God of War games, right?
With the guy saying, Boy.
I haven't played them, but I know about the meme.
Just have it be.
What are you playing?
Boy?
Yeah, boy.
Playing the sack?
Oh, like Isaac?
I see.
Dude, have you guys seen that new movie in the cinema?
The space one.
I haven't seen it myself, but is it good?
With Ryan Gosling.
I was thinking of going to the cinema to check it out.
I heard it's good.
Project Hail Mary, yeah, that one.
Can you guys recommend it?
If you've seen it, that is.
Oh, it's based on a book?
I didn't know that.
Or maybe I did know that, actually.
Project Hail Mary.
People say it's really... Yeah, that's what I heard, too.
The thing is, though, with so many people praising it, I can't...
I'm probably going to be disappointed.
Because I don't know what it is, but the last, maybe, 10 years or so...
I feel like I can't trust people's or online ratings anymore.
There's a movie that has an 8 on IMDB, which, to me, means this movie is the shit.
If that has an 8 on IMDB, that means, usually, or it used to mean, that it was really good, like, universally.
Then I check it out, and I actually hate it.
So I'm like, what is going on right now?
How is this movie an 8 on IMDB?
You know?
Rating inflation, for sure.
Yeah, multiple opinions, but I don't know what it is.
Maybe I'm just getting old, and, you know, I'm becoming one of those old complaining people.
Back in my day, ratings used to matter.
I do feel like movies are getting kind of worse.
Like, just across the board.
There are still bangers that are, like, amazing, but, you know...
I don't really care about that, Cheesemo.
Like, people always say to me, oh, do you hate when movies get the science wrong and stuff?
Because you're, like, did science yourself?
No!
I don't give a shit.
I can buy into whatever, honestly.
Let's have a black hole that is alive and has eyes.
Sure, go for it.
That sounds awesome.
I think it's cool, still, if they want to make it scientifically accurate.
That's cool, too.
But I don't mind if it's not.
As long as the acting is good and the story is good, then I'm in.
As long as it's a good story being told, right?
Interstellar hater?
No, I'm an interstellar lover.
I love that game.
Game.
Movie.
Although I wish that was a game for Interstellar.
I would play it.
Imagine, I was talking about something completely different.
Interstellar sucks.
Well, some people think other people don't.
I mean, there are some certified classics that most people say are, like, amazing.
I am not a big fan of some of them.
Like, for example, I think I enjoy...
What's that movie called?
2001 A Space Odyssey?
Half of that movie, to me, is, like, really good.
And then the other half is, like, fucking terrible.
There are certain parts of that movie that I just... it's too boring.
It's just not fun.
And then there are moments that are so good.
So, for me, it's, like, a really average movie, you know?
I can't ever watch that movies because I already got spoiled.
Oh, you were talking about Interstellar or...?
Yes, I am aware of the Back Room's movie.
I saw that the new trailer came out.
It had, like, 5 million views.
I know what the concept is.
It's, like, this weird, uh...
I'm not gonna say anything, actually.
People don't know about it.
I'm not an expert on that stuff, but it sounds interesting.
I'm down for it.
I just love the idea, the concept behind the Back Rooms, you know?
I think that it could be really cool.
Okay, guys, it's time for me to eat!
Rye bread with toppings, thank you so much for watching, watching me tilt out of my mind halfway through, and then somehow coming out on top.
That was actually a crazy situation.
The situation was crazy!
And that doesn't happen often.
I'll see you next time.
Bye-bye.